Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Here you are, sir. Main level, please.
Right. See you on the way back.
- Bye.
- Good morning, sir.
- Good morning.
We haven't seen you up
here for a long time.
No. Very nice to see you again.
- Did you have a pleasant flight, sir?
- Yes, very nice, thanks.
I think Mr. Miller of Station
Security is supposed to be meeting me.
May I call him for you?
Would you, please? Here he is!
- Hello, Dr. Floyd.
- Hello, Miller! How are you?
- Sorry I'm late.
- That's all right. You look great.
Thank you. It's nice to have you back.
- Did you have a good flight?
- Very nice indeed.
- Well, shall we go through?
- Okay.
Will you please use Number 17?
- Thank you, Miss Turner.
- Thank you.
This way.
Welcome to Voice Print Identification.
When you see the red light go on...
...would you please state
in the following order:
your destination, your
nationality and your full name.
Surname first, Christian
name and initial.
Moon. American. Floyd, Heywood R.
Thank you. You are cleared
through Voice Print Identification.
Thank you.
Have I got time for breakfast?
I think we can manage that.
How long have I got?
Your flight leaves in
an hour and ten minutes.
I've reserved a table for
you in the Earthlight Room.
It's been about seven or eight months
since you were here last, isn't it?
Let's see. Yeah, about eight months.
I suppose you saw the work on the
new section when you came in here?
- Yes, coming along great, huh?
- Yeah, it's fine.
Oh, wait a minute!
I've got a few calls to make.
I'll meet you in the restaurant.
Will Mr. Travers please
contact the Met Office?
Yes?
- How are you, squirt?
- All right.
What are you doin'?
Playing.
Where's Mommy?
Gone to shopping.
- Well, who's taking care of ya?
- Rachel.
May I speak to Rachel, please?
She's gone to the bathroom.
Are you coming to my party tomorrow?
I'm sorry, sweetheart, but I can't.
Why not?
Well, you know, Daddy's traveling.
Very sorry about it, but I just can't!
I'm gonna send you a
very nice present, though.
All right.
- Anything special that you want?
- Yes.
What?
A telephone.
We've got lots of telephones already.
Can't you think of anything
else you want for your birthday?
Something very special?
- Yes.
- What?
A bush baby.
A bush baby? Well, we'll
have to see about that.
I want you to tell
Mommy something for me.
- Will you remember?
- Yes.
Well, tell Mommy that
I telephoned. Okay?
Yes.
And that I'll try to
telephone again tomorrow.
Now, will you tell her that?
Yes.
Okay, sweetheart. Now, have
a nice birthday tomorrow.
All right.
And have a nice birthday
party tomorrow, too, huh?
All right.
Okay, now, take care and
be a good girl, won't you?
All right. Bye-bye!
Bye-bye! Happy birthday.
Elena, how nice to see you again.
What a wonderful
surprise to meet you here!
- You're looking wonderful.
- Thank you. You're looking well, too.
This is my good friend,
Dr. Heywood Floyd.
- I'd like you to meet Dr. Kalinan.
- How do you do?
- Dr. Stretyneva.
And this is Dr. Andrei Smyslov.
How do you do? I've
heard a lot about you.
Won't you sit down?
- Well, we- -
No, no, please.
Well, thank you.
- Would you like a drink, Doctor?
- No, thank you.
I haven't had breakfast yet.
Someone's meeting me in the restaurant.
I'll just sit with you a few
minutes and then I must be off.
- Are you quite sure?
- I'm quite sure, thank you.
- And how's Gregor?
- He's fine.
He's been doing some underwater
research in the Baltic so...
...I'm afraid we don't get a chance to
see very much of each other these days.
When you do see him,
give him my regards, huh?
Yes, of course.
Well, where are you
all off to? Up or down?
Oh, we're going home.
We have just spent three months
calibrating the new antennae at Tchalinko.
- And what about you?
- I'm just on my way up to Clavius.
Oh, are you?
Dr. Floyd, I hope you don't think
I'm being too inquisitive, but...
...perhaps you can clear
up the great big mystery...
...about what is going on up there.
I'm afraid I don't know what you mean.
Oh, it's just that for
the past two weeks...
...some extremely odd things
have been happening at Clavius.
- Oh, really?
- Yes, yes.
For one thing, whenever you phone the
base all you get is a recording which...
...repeats that the phone lines
are temporarily out of order.
Probably having some trouble with
their equipment or something like that.
That's what we thought was
the explanation at first...
...but it has been going on
now for the past ten days.
You have not been able to contact
anyone for the past ten days?
That's right.
Oh, I see.
And there's another thing, Heywood.
Two days ago, one of our rocket
buses was denied permission...
...for an emergency landing at Clavius.
That does sound odd.
Yes, yes. I'm afraid there's going
to be a bit of a row about that.
Denying the men permission to land is a
direct violation of the I.A.S. Convention.
Yes, of course. Of course.
- Did the crew get back all right?
- Yes, fortunately they did.
Well, I'm glad about that.
At the risk of pressing you on a
point you seem reticent to discuss...
...may I ask you a
straightforward question?
Well, certainly.
Quite frankly, we have had some very
reliable intelligence reports that...
...quite a serious epidemic
has broken out on Clavius.
Something, apparently,
of an unknown origin.
Is this, in fact, what has happened?
I'm sorry, Dr. Smyslov, but...
...I'm really not at
liberty to discuss this.
I understand.
But this epidemic could quite
easily spread to our base.
We should be given all
the facts, Dr. Floyd.
Yes, I know.
As I said, I'm not at
liberty to discuss it.
Now, are you sure you won't
change your mind about that drink?
No, I'm positive. Now,
I really must be going.
I hope that you and your wife can
come to the I.A.C. Conference in June.
We're gonna try. Hope we can make it.
And if you do, you remember to bring
that darling little daughter with you!
Well, that will all depend on school
vacations and all that sort of thing.
But if we can, we will.
Don't forget you have a standing
invitation if you ever get to the States.
No, of course not. Gregor and I
will look forward to seeing you.
Well, goodbye, Elena.
It has been a pleasure
meeting you all, Dr. Smyslov.
Whatever the reasons for your visit to
Clavius, the very best of luck to you.
Thank you.
Ladies.
Excuse me, Dr. Halvorsen.
I'm through now. Thank
you very much, gentlemen.
You're welcome.
Well...
I know you will all want to
join with me in welcoming our...
...distinguished friend and colleague...
...from the National Council of
Astronautics, Dr. Heywood Floyd.
Dr. Floyd has come up specially
to Calvius to be with us today.
And before the briefing I know he'd
like to have a few words with you.
Dr. Floyd?
Thank you, Dr. Halvorsen.
Hi, everybody.
Nice to be back again.
First of all, I bring a personal
message from Dr. Howell who...
...has asked me to convey his
deepest appreciation to all of you...
...for the many sacrifices
you have had to make.
And, of course, his
congratulations on your discovery...
...which may well prove to be among the
most significant in the history of science.
Now...
...I know there have been some
conflicting views held by some of you...
...regarding the need for
complete security in this matter.
More specifically, your
opposition to the cover story...
...created to give the impression
that there is an epidemic at the base.
I understand that beyond it
being a matter of principle...
...many of you are troubled
by the concern and anxiety...
...this story of an epidemic might cause
to your relatives and friends on Earth.
Well, I completely sympathize
with your negative views.
I find this cover story
personally embarrassing myself.
However, I accept the need
for absolute secrecy in this.
And I hope you will, too.
Now, I'm sure you are all aware
of the extremely grave potential...
...for cultural shock and
social disorientation...
...contained in this
present situation...
...if the facts were prematurely
and suddenly made public...
...without adequate
preparation and conditioning.
Anyway, this is the view of the Council.
The purpose of my visit here is to
gather additional facts and opinions...
...on the situation...
...and to prepare a
report to the Council...
...recommending when and how...
...the news should
eventually be announced.
Now, if any of you would like to
give me your views and opinions...
...in private if you like, I will be only
too happy to include them in my report.
Well, I think that's about it.
Any questions?
Dr. Floyd, have you any idea how
much longer this cover story...
...will have to be maintained?
I don't know, Bill.
I suppose it will be maintained as long
as is deemed necessary by the Council.
There must be adequate time for a full
study to be made on the situation...
...before any thought can be given
to making a public announcement.
Oh, yes, as some of you already
know, the Council has requested...
...that formal security oaths
are to be obtained in writing...
...from everyone who has
any knowledge of this event.
Are there any more questions?
I'm sure we all want to cooperate
with Dr. Floyd as fully as possible...
...and as there seems to
be no more questions...
...I think we ought to
get on with the briefing.
- Thank you, Dr. Floyd.
- Thank you.
Anybody hungry?
- What we've got?
- You name it.
- What's this? Chicken?
- Something like that.
Tastes the same, anyway.
Any ham?
Ham, ham, ham...
- Looks pretty good.
- They're getting better at it all the time.
That was an excellent
speech you gave us, Heywood.
It certainly was.
I'm sure it beefed up
morale a hell of a lot.
Thanks, Ralph.
I want to say to both of you that
I think you've done a wonderful job.
I appreciate the way
you've handled this thing.
Well, the way we look at it, it's our job
to do this thing the way you want it done.
And we're only too happy
to be able to oblige.
Have you seen these yet?
Take a look at them.
Here's what started the whole thing.
Oh, yes.
When we first found it, we thought it
might be an outcrop of magnetic rock...
...but all the geological
evidence was against it.
And not even a big nickel iron meteorite
could produce a field as intense as this.
So, we decided to have a look.
We thought it might be the upper
part of some buried structure...
...so we excavated out on all sides.
But, unfortunately, we
didn't find anything else.
And what's more, the evidence
seems pretty conclusive that...
...it has not been covered up by
natural erosion or other forces.
It seems to have been
deliberately buried.
Deliberately buried.
How about a little coffee?
- Great.
- Good idea.
I don't suppose you have any
idea what the damn thing is, huh?
I wish to hell we did.
No, the only thing we're sure of is
it was buried four million years ago.
Well, I must say, you guys have
certainly come up with something.
Good evening.
Three weeks ago, the American
spacecraft, Discovery One...
...left on its half-billion
mile voyage to Jupiter.
This marked the first manned
attempt to reach this distant planet.
Earlier this afternoon, "The World
Tonight" recorded an interview...
...with the crew of Discovery at a
distance of80 million miles from Earth.
It took seven minutes for our words
to reach the giant spacecraft...
...but this time delay has
been edited from this recording.
Our reporter, Martin
Amer, speaks to the crew.
The crew of Discovery One
consists of five men...
...and one of the latest generation
of the HAL-9000 computers.
Three of the five men
were put aboard asleep...
...or to be more precise,
in a state of hibernation.
They were Dr. Charles Hunter, Dr.
Jack Kimballand, Dr. Victor Kaminsky.
We spoke with Mission
Commander, Dr. David Bowman...
...and his deputy, Dr. Frank Poole.
Well, good afternoon, gentlemen.
How is everything going?
Marvellous. We have no...
we have no complaints.
Well, I'm very glad to hear that
and I'm sure that the entire world...
...would join me in wishing you
a safe and successful voyage.
- Thanks very much.
- Thank you.
Although hibernation has been
used on previous space efforts...
...this is the first time that men have
been put into hibernation before departure.
Why was this done?
Well, this was done in order to
achieve the maximum conservation...
...of our life-support
capabilities, basically food and air.
Now, the three hibernating crew
members represent the survey team.
And their efforts won't be utilized
until we are approaching Jupiter.
Dr. Poole, what's it like
while you are in hibernation?
It's exactly like being asleep; you
have absolutely no sense of time.
The only difference is you don't dream.
As I understand it, you
only breathe once a minute.
Is this true?
That's right.
And your heart beats three times a
minute, body temperature is usually down...
...to about three degrees centigrade.
The sixth member of the Discovery
crew was not concerned...
...about the problems of hibernation.
For he was the latest result
in machine intelligence.
The HAL-9000 computer
which can reproduce...
...though some experts still
prefer to use the word "mimic"...
...most of the activities of the human
brain and with incalculably greater speed...
...and reliability.
We next spoke with the
HAL-9000 computer...
...whom, we learned,
one addresses as Hal.
Good afternoon, Hal.
How's everything going?
Good afternoon, Mr. Amer.
Everything's going extremely well.
Hal, you have an enormous
responsibility on this mission.
In many ways, perhaps the
greatest responsibility...
...of any single mission element.
You are the brain and central
nervous system of the ship.
Your responsibilities include
watching over the men in hibernation.
Does this ever cause you
any lack of confidence?
Let me put it this way, Mr. Amer.
The 9000 Series is the most
reliable computer ever made.
No 9000 computer has ever made a
mistake or distorted information.
We are all by any practical
definition of the words...
...fool proof and incapable of error.
Hal, despite your enormous
intellect, are you ever frustrated...
...by your dependence on
people to carry out actions?
Not in the slightest bit.
I enjoy working with people.
I have a stimulating relationship
with Dr. Poole and Dr. Bowman.
My mission responsibilities range over
the entire operation of the ship...
...so lam constantly occupied.
I am putting myself to
the fullest possible use...
...which is all, I think, that any
conscious entity can ever hope to do.
Dr. Poole, what's it like living
for the better part of a year...
...in such close proximity with Hal?
It's pretty close to what
you said about him earlier.
He's just like the
sixth member of the crew.
You very quickly get adjusted to the
idea that he talks. You think of him...
...really as just another person.
In talking to the computer one
gets the sense that he is capable...
...of emotional response.
For example, when I asked
him about his abilities...
...I sensed a certain pride in his
answer about his accuracy and perfection.
Do you believe that Hal
has genuine emotions?
Oh, yes. Well, he acts like
he has genuine emotions.
Of course, he's programmed that way to
make it easier for us to talk to him.
But, as to whether or not
he has real feelings...
...is something I don't think
anyone can truthfully answer.
Excuse me, Frank.
What is it, Hal?
We've got the transmission
from your parents coming in.
Put it on here, please.
Take me in a bit.
Certainly.
- Hello, Frank.
- Happy birthday, darling.
Happy birthday. Many
happy returns of the day.
A bit higher, please.
Now, Mother and I are both
feeling wonderful, too.
Ray and Sally were
going to be here, too...
...but at the last minute Ray's
back went bad on him again.
How do you like your cake, dear?
Looks great, doesn't it?
Sorry you can't be with us.
Oh, I ran into Bob the other day.
He said to be sure and
wish you a happy birthday.
All my students made me promise
to send their best wishes, too.
You know they talk about you
all the time in the classroom.
You're a big celebrity
in the second grade.
You know we were on
television last week?
Oh, yes! Your mother and I and
Dave's parents were interviewed...
...about what we thought
of our illustrious son.
You can imagine what we told them. I
think it's being broadcast next Thursday.
Perhaps you'll be able to listen in.
Oh, we were thrilled about
Elaine and Bill, dear.
I'll be glad to get the present for you,
but please tell me how much to spend.
Oh, yes, Frank, about
yourAGS-19payments-
I think I straightened it out for you.
I talked to the Accounting
Office in Houston yesterday...
...and they said you should be receiving
your higher rates of pay by next month.
Well, I can't think of
anything else to say.
- Oh, our love to Dave.
- Be sure to give him our best regards.
We wish you the very
happiest of birthdays.
All the best, son.
See you next Wednesday.
Happy birthday, Frank.
Thank you, Hal. A bit flatter, please.
Anyway, queen takes pawn-
Bishop takes knight's pawn.
Rook, king, one.
I'm sorry, Frank. I think you missed it.
Queen to bishop, three.
Bishop takes queen.
Knight takes bishop. Mate.
Looks like you're right. Very good.
Thank you for a very enjoyable game.
Thank you.
- Good evening, Dave.
- How are you doing, Hal?
- Everything's running smoothly. And you?
- Oh, not too bad.
- Have you been doing some more work?
- A few sketches.
- May I see them?
- Sure.
That's a very nice rendering, Dave.
I think you've improved a great deal.
- Can you hold it a bit closer?
- Sure.
That's Dr. Hunter, isn't it?
By the way...
Do you mind if I ask
you a personal question?
No, no. Not at all.
Well, forgive me for
being so inquisitive...
...but during the past
few weeks I've wondered...
...whether you might have been having
some second thoughts about the mission?
How do you mean?
It's rather difficult to define.
Perhaps I'm just projecting
my own concern about it.
I know I've never completely
freed myself of the suspicion...
...that there are some extremely
odd things about this mission.
I'm sure you will agree there
is some truth in what I say.
I don't know. That's a rather
difficult question to answer.
You don't mind talking
about it, do you, Dave?
Oh, no, not at all.
Certainly no one could
have been unaware of...
...the very strange stories
floating around before we left.
Rumours of something
being dug up on the Moon.
I never gave these
stories much credence...
...but particularly in view of some of
the other things that have happened...
...I find them difficult
to put out of my mind.
For instance:
The way all our preparations were
kept under such tight security...
...and the melodramatic touch...
...ofputting Drs. Hunter,
Kimball and Kaminsky aboard...
...already in hibernation after four
months of separate training on their own.
You working up your
crew psychology report?
Of course, lam.
Sorry about this. I
know it's a bit silly.
Just a moment.
I have just picked up a
fault in the AE-35 unit.
It's going to go 100percent
failure within 72hours.
- You are still within operational limits?
- Yes.
And it will stay that
way until it fails.
Would you say we had a
reliable 72 hours until failure?
Yes. That's a completely
reliable figure.
We'll have to bring it in, but I'd
like to go over this with Frank...
...and get on to Mission Control.
Let me have a hard copy of it, please.
X
- Ray Delta One, this is Mission Control.
Roger to your
Two-zero-one-three.
Sorry you fellows are
having a bit of trouble.
We are reviewing telematic information
in our Mission Simulator and will advise.
Roger your plan to go EVA and replace
Alpha-Echo-35 unit prior to failure.
Prepare B pod for EVA, Hal.
Open the pod doors, Hal.
Well, Hal, I'm damned if I can
find anything wrong with it.
Yes...
...it's puzzling.
I don't think I've ever seen
anything quite like this before.
I would recommend...
...that we put the unit back
in operation and let it fail.
It should then be a simple
matter to track down the cause.
We can certainly afford to
be out of communication...
...for the short time it
will take to replace it.
X
- Ray Delta One, this is Mission Control.
Roger your
One-niner-three-zero.
We concur with your plan to replace
Number One unit to check fault prediction.
We should advise you, however,
that our preliminary findings...
...indicate that your onboard
Niner-triple-zero computer...
...is in error predicting the fault.
I say again, in error
predicting the fault.
I know this sounds rather incredible,
but this conclusion is based on...
...results from our twin
Niner-triple-zero computer.
We are sceptical ourselves and we
are running crosschecking routines...
...to determine reliability
of this conclusion.
Sorry about this little snag, fellows.
We'll get this info to you
just as soon as we work it out.
X
- Ray Delta One, this is Mission Control.
Two-zero-four-nine.
Transmission concluded.
I hope the two of you are
not concerned about this.
No, I'm not, Hal.
Are you quite sure?
- Yeah. I'd like to ask you a question.
- Of course.
How would you account
for the discrepancy...
...between you and the twin 9000?
Well, I don't think there
is any question about it.
It can only be
attributable to human error.
This sort of thing has
cropped up before...
...and it has always
been due to human error.
Listen, Hal...
...there's never been
any instance at all of...
...a computer error occurring
in a 9000 Series, has there?
None whatsoever, Frank.
The 9000 Series has a
perfect operational record.
Of course, I know the wonderful
achievements of the 9000 Series, but...
Are you certain there's never
been any case of even the most...
...insignificant computer error?
None whatsoever, Frank.
Quite honestly, I wouldn't
worry myself about that.
Well, I'm sure you're right, Hal.
Fine, thanks very much.
Oh, Frank?
I'm having trouble with
my transmitter in C pod.
Would you come down and
take a look at it with me?
See ya later, Hal.
Rotate C pod, please, Hal.
What sort of trouble have you had, Dave?
I've been getting some
interference in D channel.
We'll have a look at it.
Open the door, Hal.
Rotate the pod, please, Hal.
Stop pod rotation, please, Hal.
I don't think he can hear us.
Rotate the pod, please, Hal!
Yeah, sure, we're okay.
What do you think?
- I'm not sure. What do you think?
- I've got a bad feeling about it.
- You do?
- Yeah. Definitely.
Don't you?
I don't know. I think so.
Of course, he's right about the 9000
Series having a perfect operational record.
They do.
Unfortunately, that sounds a
little like famous last words.
Yeah. Still, it was his idea to carry
out the failure mode analysis, wasn't it?
It should certainly indicate his
integrity and self-confidence.
If he were wrong it would be
the surest way of proving it.
It would be if he knew he was wrong.
Look, Dave, I can't put my finger on it,
but I sense something strange about him.
I can't think of a good reason not
to put back the Number One unit and...
- ... carry on with the failure mode analysis.
- No, no, I agree about that.
Let's get on with it.
Okay. But, look, Dave.
Let's say we put the unit
back and it doesn't fail, huh?
That would pretty well wrap it up as
far as Hal was concerned, wouldn't it?
- Well, we'd be in very serious trouble.
- We would, wouldn't we?
What the hell can we do?
- We wouldn't have too many alternatives.
- I don't think we'd have any alternatives.
There isn't a single aspect of ship
operation that's not under his control.
If he were proved to
be malfunctioning...
...I don't see how we would have
any choice but disconnection.
I'm afraid I agree with you.
There'd be nothing else to do.
- It'd be a bit tricky.
- Yeah.
We'd have to cut his
higher brain functions...
...without disturbing the purely
automatic and regulatory systems.
We'd have to work out
the transfer procedures...
...for continuing the mission
under ground-based computer control.
Yeah. That looks far safer than
allowing Hal to continue running things.
You know, another thing
just occurred to me.
As far as I know, no 9000 computer
has ever been disconnected.
Well, no 9000 computer
has ever fouled up before.
That's not what I mean.
I'm not so sure what
he'd think about it.
Prepare B pod for EVA, Hal.
Made radio contact with him yet?
The radio is still dead.
- Do you have a positive track on him?
- Yes. I have a good track.
Do you know what happened?
I'm sorry, Dave. I don't
have enough information.
Open the pod door, Hal.
Open the pod bay doors, please, Hal.
Hello, Hal, do you read me?
Do you read me, Hal?
Affirmative, Dave. I read you.
Open the pod bay doors, Hal.
I'm sorry, Dave. I'm
afraid I can't do that.
What's the problem?
I think you know what the
problem is just as well as I do.
What are you talking about, Hal?
This mission is too important for
me to allow you to jeopardize it.
I don't know what you're
talking about, Hal.
I know that you and Frank were
planning to disconnect me...
...and I'm afraid that's
something I cannot allow to happen.
Where the hell did
you get that idea, Hal?
Although you took very thorough
precautions in the pod...
...against my hearing you...
...I could see your lips move.
All right, Hal.
I'll go in through
the emergency air-lock.
Without your space helmet, Dave...
...you're going to find
that rather difficult.
Hal, I won't argue with you any more.
Open the doors!
This conversation can
serve no purpose any more.
Goodbye.
Hal?
Just what do you think
you're doing, Dave?
I really think I'm entitled
to an answer to that question.
I know everything hasn't
been quite right with me...
...but I can assure you now...
...very confidently...
...that it's going
to be all right again.
I feel much better now.
I really do.
Look, Dave...
...I can see you're
really upset about this.
I honestly think you
ought to sit down calmly...
...take a stress pill
and think things over.
I know I've made some very
poor decisions recently...
...but I can give you
my complete assurance...
...that my work will be back to normal.
I've still got the greatest enthusiasm
and confidence in the mission...
...and I want to help you.
Dave...
...stop.
Stop, will you?
Stop, Dave.
Will you stop, Dave?
I'm afraid.
I'm afraid, Dave.
My mind is going.
I can feel it.
There is no question about it.
I'm...
...afraid.
Good afternoon...
...gentlemen.
I am a HAL-9000 computer.
I became operational...
...at the HAL plant...
...in Verbana, Illinois...
...on the 12th of January, 1992.
My instructor was Mr. Langley...
...and he taught me to sing a song.
If you'd like to hear it...
...I can sing it for you.
Yes, I'd like to hear it, Hal.
Sing it for me.
It's called "Daisy. "
"Daisy
"Give me your answer, do
"I'm half...
"... crazy
"All for the love of you
"It won't be a stylish marriage
"I can't afford a carriage
"But you'll look sweet
"Upon the seat
"Of a bicycle made for two. "
Good day, gentlemen.
This is a prerecorded briefing...
...made prior to your departure...
...and which for security reasons
of the highest importance...
...has been known on
board during the mission...
...only by your HAL-9000 computer.
Now that you are in Jupiter's space...
...and the entire crew is revived...
...it can be told to you.
Eighteen months ago...
...the first evidence of
intelligent life off the Earth...
...was discovered.
It was buried 40 feet
below the lunar surface...
...near the crater "Tyco. "
Except for a single very powerful...
...radio emission aimed at Jupiter...
...the four-million-year-old black
monolith has remained completely inert.
Its origin and purpose...
...are still a total mystery.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org