Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
[ Electronic Beep ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Thud ]
[ Respirator Hissing ]
[ Man ]
Bio readouts are all in the green.
Looks like she's alive.
Well, there goes
our salvage, guys.
How are we today?
Ohh. Terrible.
Well, better than
yesterday, at least.
Where am I?
You're safe.
You're at Gateway Station.
Been here a couple of days.
You were pretty groggy at first,
but now you're okay.
Oh, looks like
you've got a visitor.
Jonesy. Come here.
Hey, come here.
How are you,
you stupid cat?
How are you?
Where have you been?
Guess you two
have met, huh?
I'm Burke. Carter Burke.
I work for the company,
but don't let that fool you.
I'm really an okay guy.
I'm glad to see you're
feeling a little better.
They tell me that all
the weakness and disorientation
should pass soon.
That's just natural side effects
of such an unusually long hypersleep,
or something like that.
What do you mean?
How long
was I out there?
[ Woman On P.A. ]
Inhalation Therapy, report to-
Has no one discussed
this with you yet?
No.
But, I mean...
I don't... recognize
this place.
No, I know. Uh-
Okay. It's just that,
uh, this might be
a shock to you.
It's long-
How long?
Please.
57 years.
What?
That's the thing.
You were out there
for 57 years.
What happened was
you had drifted
right through the core systems.
And it's really
just blind luck...
that a deep-salvage team
found you when they did.
It's one in a thousand,
really.
I think you're damn lucky
to be alive, kiddo. You could
be floating out there forever.
[ Stammering ]
You- You okay?
- [ Hisses ]
- Uhh-
[ Heart Pounding ]
- [ Hisses ]
- Uuh!
You okay?
[ Groaning ]
- [ Hisses ]
- Oh-h-h! Oh, God!
Nurse! Please!
God!
Someone get in here now!
[ Screaming ]
Now!
- Hold!
- Please.
Hold on!
Kill me!
No!
[ Gasping ]
Uh!
Bad dreams again?
You want something
to help you sleep?
No.
[ Sighs ]
I've slept enough.
Jonesy.
Come here.
[ Meows ]
Shh.
It's all right.
It's all right now.
[ Purring ]
It's over.
[ Birds Chirping ]
[ Chirping Stops ]
[ Woman On P.A. ]
Dr Hirsch, 334. Dr. Hirsch, 334.
Hi. Sorry I'm late.
I've been running behind
all morning.
Is there any word
about my daughter?
Uh... I really think
we should worry
about the hearing now.
'Cause we don't have a lot of time, okay?
I read your deposition, and it's great.
If you just stick to that,
I think we'll be fine.
The thing to remember is,
there're gonna be a lot
of heavyweights in there.
You've got feds
and Interstellar
Commerce Commission,
Colonial Administration,
insurance company guys-
Do you have any news
about my daughter?
Well, we did come up
with some information.
Why don't we sit down?
I was hoping to wait
until after the inquest.
Um-
"Amanda Ripley-McClaren"-
married name, I guess-
"Age 66."
And that was at
the time of her death,
which was two years ago.
I'm real sorry.
Amy.
She was cremated and interred
at Westlake Repository,
Little Chute, Wisconsin.
No children. I checked.
[ Briefcase Closes ]
[ Inhales Sharply ]
I promised her...
that I'd be home
for her birthday.
Her 11th birthday.
[ Choking Up ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Man #1 ]
I'djust like to go, uh-
back to this point about
the override destruct order.
[ Man #2 ]
Is it in the file?
I don't understand this.
We have been here
for three and a half hours.
Now, how many different ways
do you want me to tell
the same story?
Look at it from
our perspective,
please.
Please?
Now, you freely admit to
detonating the engines of,
and thereby destroying,
an M-class starsreighter,
a rather expensive piece
of hardware.
Forty-two million
in adjusted dollars.
That's minus payload,
of course.
The lifeboat's flight recorder
corroborates some elements
of your account,
in that, for reasons unknown,
the Nostromo set down
on LV-426,
an unsurveyed planet at that time,
that it resumed its course...
and was subsequently
set for self-destruct
by you for reasons unknown.
Not for reasons unknown.
I told you.
We set down there
on company orders to get this thing,
which destroyed my crew...
and your expensive ship.
The analysis team,
which went over the lifeboat
centimeter by centimeter,
found no physical evidence
of the creature you describe.
Good!
That's because I blew it
out of the goddamn air lock,
like I said.
Are there any species
like this hostile organism
on LV-426?
No. It's a rock.
No indigenous life.
Did I.Q.'s just drop sharply
while I was away?
Ma'am, I already said
it was not indigenous.
It was a derelict spacecraft.
It was an alien ship.
It was not from there.
Do you get it?
We homed in on its beacon.
And found something
never recorded once...
in over 300 surveyed worlds.
- "A creature that gestates
inside a living human host."
- Yes.
These are your words.
"And has concentrated acid
for blood."
That's right.
Look. I can see
where this is going,
but I'm telling you
that those things exist.
- Thank you, Officer Ripley.
That will be all.
- Please. You're not listening to me.
Kane, the crew member-
Kane, who went into that ship,
said he saw
thousands of eggs there.
Thousands.
Thank you.
That will be all.
Goddamn it,
that's not all!
Because if one of those things
gets down here,
then that will be all!
Then all of this-
this bullshit that you think
is so important-
You can just kiss
all of that good-bye!
It is the finding
of this court of inquiry that...
Warrant Officer E. Ripley,
NOC14472,
has acted with
questionable judgment...
and is unfit to hold
an I.C.C. license
as a commercial flight officer.
Said license is hereby
suspended indefinitely.
Now, no criminal charges
will be filed against you
at this time,
and you are released
on your own recognizance...
for a six-month period
ofpsychometric probation,
to include monthly review
by an I.C.C. psychiatric technician.
These proceedings are closed.
That could have
been better.
Look, I think the-
Ripley?
Van Leuwen.
Why don't you
just check out LV-426?
Because I don't have to.
There have been people there
for over 20 years,
and they never complained
about any hostile organism.
What do you mean? What people?
Terraformers.
Planet engineers.
They go in, set up these
big atmosphere processors
to make the air breathable.
Takes decades.
It's what we call
a "Shake 'N Bake" colony.
How many are there?
How many colonists?
I don't know-
60, maybe 70 families.
Do you mind?
Families.
Jesus.
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Low Chattering ]
[ Woman On P.A.,
Indistinct ]
[ Machines Clacking ]
I'll be down
in maintenance, okay?
Al!
What?
Hey, Al.
Remember you sent
some wildcatters...
out to the middle
of nowhere last week,
out past the Ilium Range?
- Yeah, what?
- One of them's on the horn,
a mom-and-pop survey team.
He says he's onto something.
He wants to know if
his claim will be honored.
Why wouldn't his claim
be honored?
Well, because you sent them to that
particular middle-of-nowhere
on company orders, maybe.
I don't know.
Christ! Some honch in
a cushy office on Earth...
says, "Go look at
a grid reference."
We look.
They don't say why,
and I don't ask.
I don't ask, because it takes
two weeks to get an answer out here,
and the answer is always-
[ Together ]
"Don't ask."
So what do l
tell this guy?
[ Sighs ]
Tell him as far as
I'm concerned, if he
finds something, it is his.
Lydecker?
What?
[ Giggling ]
You kids know you're not
supposed to be on this level!
Go on!
Get outta here!
[ Giggling ]
[ Boy ] Do too. You go
in places we can't fit.
So? That's why I'm the best.
Knock it off! I catch either
of you playing in the air ducts
again, l'll tan your hides.
Mom, all the kids play-
Wait a minute.
Annie, come and have
a look at this, will ya?
Folks, we have
scored big this time.
What is it, Dad?
I'm not sure.
Let's see if we can't get a
closer look at this thing, maybe
through that crack there on the side.
- Shouldn't we call in?
- Let's wait till we know
what to call it in as.
[ Brakes Hiss ]
[ Dad ] That's about as close
as we can get.
Should we take
a look inside?
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Wind Whistling ]
You two stay inside.
I mean it.
We'll be right back.
Okay.
Bye.
[ Thunderclap ]
[ Radio Chatter, Indistinct ]
Huh?
Timmy, they've been gone
a long time.
It'll be okay, Newt.
Dad knows what he's doing.
[ Banging ]
Mayday, Mayday! This is Alpha Kilo
Two Four Niner calling!
This is Alpha Kilo
Two Four Niner!
[ Screaming ]
Alpha Kilo
Two Four Niner calling!
[ Meowing ]
[ Doorbell Beeps ]
[ Clears Throat ]
Hiya, Ripley.
This is Lieutenant Gorman...
of the Colonial
Marine Corps-
Ripley,
we have to talk.
We've lost contact
with the colony on LV-426.
I don't believe this.
You guys throw me at the wolves,
and now you want me
to go back out there?
Forget it.
It's not my problem.
Can I finish?
No.
There's no way.
Ripley, you wouldn't
be going in
with the troops.
I can guarantee
your safety.
These Colonial Marines
are very tough hombres.
They're packing
state-of-the-art
firepower.
There's nothing
they can't handle.
- Lieutenant, am I right?
- That's true.
We've been trained
to deal with situations
like this.
Then you don't need me.
I'm not a soldier.
[ Burke ]
Yeah, but we don't know exactly
what's going on out there.
It mayjust be
a downed transmitter,
okay?
But if it's not,
I would like you there
as an adviser,
and that's all.
What's your interest
in all this?
Why are you going?
Corporation cofinanced
that colony,
along with
Colonial Administration.
We're getting into a lot
of terraforming now.
"Building Better Worlds"-
Yeah, yeah.
I saw the commercial.
Look, I don't have time
for this. I've got
to get to work.
Oh, right. I heard you're
working the cargo docks.
That's right.
Running loaders and forklifts,
that sort of thing?
Yeah. So?
Nothing. I think it's great
that you're keeping busy.
And I know it's the only
thing that you could get.
There's nothing wrong
with it.
What would you say
if I told you I could
get you reinstated...
as a flight officer?
The company's already agreed
to pick up your contract.
If I go.
Yeah, if you go.
Come on.
That's a second chance, kiddo.
I think, personally,
for you, it would be
the best thing in the world...
to get out there
and face this thing,
get back on the horse.
Spare me, Burke.
I've had my psych evaluation
this month.
Yeah, I know. I've read it. You wake
up every night. Your sheets
are soaking with sweat-
I said no,
and I mean it!
Now, please leave.
I am not going back.
And I am- I would not be
any good to you if I did.
Okay. Shh.
Would you
do me a favor?
Just think about it.
Thanks
for the coffee.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
[ Meows ]
[ Screaming, Panting ]
Oh!
[ Sobbing ]
[ Water Running ]
[ Beeping ]
Hello.
Ripley.
You okay?
Just tell me
one thing, Burke.
You're going out there
to destroy them, right?
Not to study, not to bring back,
but to wipe them out.
That's the plan.
You have my word on it.
All right. I'm in.
I think that-
And you,
you little shithead,
[ Chuckles ]
you're staying here.
[ Creaking ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Whirring ]
Mmm.
[ Coughing ]
[ Groans ]
They ain't payin' us
enough for this, man.
Not enough
to have to wake up
to your face, Drake.
What?
Is that a joke?
Oh, I wish it were.
Hey, Hicks. Man, you look
just like I feel.
[ Grunts ]
- [ Coughing ]
- All right, sweethearts.
What are you waiting for?
Breakfast in bed?
Another glorious day
in the corps.
A day in the Marine Corps
is like a day on the farm-
every meal's a banquet,
every paycheck a fortune,
every formation a parade.
I love the corps!
Christ!
Man, this floor is freezing!
What do you want me to do?
Fetch your slippers for ya?
Gee, would you, sir? I'd like that.
Look into my eye.
Fall in, people.
Come on. Let's go.
I hate this job.
Crowe, Wierzbowski.
Come on. On your feet.
We got some slack coming, right?
You had three weeks
on your back, Frost.
What do you want?
[ Frost ]
I'm talking about breathing,
not this frozen shit.
[ Dietrich ]
Yeah, Top. How 'bout it?
[Apone ]
All right. First assembly's
in 15, people. Shag it.
Hey, mira.
Who's Snow White?
She's supposed to be
some kind of consultant.
Apparently,
she saw an alien once.
Whoopee-fuckin'-do!
Hey, I'm impressed.
iQue bonita!
Hey, Vasquez.
Have you ever been
mistaken for a man?
No. Have you?
Ha, ha!
Oh, Vasquez.
You're just too bad.
Uhh!
[ Chattering ]
Hey, Top,
what's the op?
It's a rescue mission.
You'll love it.
There's some juicy
colonists' daughters we have
to rescue from their virginity.
[ Spunkmeyer]
Dumb-ass colonists.
What's this crap
supposed to be?
Vasquez.
Corn bread, I think.
It's good for you, boy.
Eat it.
Hey, sure wouldn't mind
getting some more
of that Arcturian poontang.
- Remember that time?
- Yeah. Except the one
that you had was male.
Doesn't matter
when it's Arcturian.
Hey, Bishop, man.
Do the thing with the knife.
Oh, please.
Oh, come on. Yeah.
[ All Goading ]
All right! Yeah.
- I don't want to see that, man.
- Come on, man.
All right. All right.
Hey, what are you doing, man?
What are you doing?
Come on.
Quit messing around, Drake.
Hudson, shut up !
- Bishop, hey, man.
- [ Drake ] Do it, Bishop!
Hey! Not me, man!
Quit messing around!
Yeah, you! Don't move.
Trust me.
Aah!
[Apone ]
All right. Knock it off,
knock it off.
- Thank you.
- [ Drake Chuckles ]
There you go,
short shit.
Enjoy your meal.
That wasn't funny, man.
Lieutenant Gorman?
Mr. Burke?
Yeah, thanks.
Looks like the new lieutenant's
too good to eat with
the rest of us grunts.
Boy's definitely got
a corncob up his ass.
[ Burke ]
Thought you
never miss, Bishop.
You never said anything about
an android being on board.
Why not?
[ Chuckles ]
It never-
never occurred to me.
It's just common practice.
We always have
a synthetic on board.
I prefer the term
"artificial person" myself.
Right.
- Is there a problem?
- [ Burke ] I'm sorry.
I don't know why
I didn't even-
Ripley's last trip out,
the syn- the artificial person
malfunctioned.
- Malfunctioned?
- There were problems and
a few deaths were involved.
I'm shocked.
Was it an older model?
The Hyperdyne Systems
1 20-A2.
That explains it then.
The A2s always were
a bit twitchy.
That could never happen now
with our behavioral inhibitors.
It is impossible for me to harm,
or by omission ofaction, allow
to be harmed, a human being.
- You sure you
don't want some?
- [ Clattering ]
You just stay away from me,
Bishop. You got that straight?
Guess she don't like
the corn bread, either.
[ Chattering ]
[ Apone ] Squad, ten-hut!
Officer on deck!
As you were.
Quickly, quickly.
Settle down.
All right.
Listen up!
Morning, marines. l'm sorry we
didn't have time to brief you
people before we left Gateway-
[ Hudson ]
Sir?
What is it, Hicks?
Hudson, sir.
He's Hicks.
What's the question?
Is this gonna be
a stand-up fight, sir,
or another bug hunt?
All we know is that
there's still no contact
with the colony...
and that a xenomorph
may be involved.
Excuse me, sir.
A what?
A xenomorph.
It's a bug hunt.
- What exactly are
we dealing with here?
- Ripley.
I'll tell you
what I know.
We set down
on LV-426.
One ofour crew members was
brought back on board with
something attached to his face,
some kind of parasite.
We tried to get it off.
It wouldn't come off.
Later, it seemed to come off
by itselfand die.
Kane seemed fine.
We were all having dinner,
and, um,
it must have laid something
inside his throat,
some sort of embryo.
He started- Um, he-
[ Vasquez ]
Look, man.
I only need
to know one thing-
where they are.
Yo, Vasquez.
Kick ass.
Anytime, anywhere.
Right, right. Somebody said
"alien." She thought they said
"illegal alien" and signed up.
Fuck you, man.
Anytime,
anywhere.
Are you finished?
I hope you're right.
I really do.
Yeah, okay, right.
Thank you, Ripley.
We also have Ripley's
report on disk.
I suggest you study it.
Because just one of those things
managed to wipe out my entire crew
in less than 24 hours.
And if the colonists
have found that ship,
then there's no telling...
how many of them
have been exposed.
Do you understand?
Anyway, we have it on disk,
so you better look at it.
Any questions?
What is it, Private?
How do I get out of this
chickenshit outfit?
You secure that shit,
Hudson.
All right.
Now listen up.
I want this thing
to go smooth...
and by the numbers.
I want D.C.S.
and tactical database
assimilation by 0830.
[ All Scoffing ]
Ordinance loading, weapons strip
and drop-ship prep details...
will have
seven hours.
Oh, come on.
Now, move it,
people!
All right, sweethearts.
You heard the man,
and you know the drill.
Assholes and elbows!
Hudson, come here.
Come here.
I don't care if you
are short, Hudson.
Get it done.
Hey, Sarge.
You'll get lip cancer
smoking those.
Corporal, I want this
loading lock sealed.
Now!
How many more you got,
Spunkmeyer?
Last one.
Good. Take it away.
[ Whirring, Thudding ]
Clear behind.
Did you check number three?
Let me see that.
Hi. I feel like kind of
a fifth wheel around here.
Is there anything I can do?
I don't know.
Is there anything
you can do?
Well, I can drive
that loader.
I have a Class 2 rating.
Be my guest.
[ Whirring ]
- Where you want it?
- [ Chuckles ]
[ Laughing ]
Bay 12, please.
[ Engines Revving ]
[Apone ] All right,
sweethearts. We're a team, and
there's nothing to worry about.
We come here,
and we gonna conquer,
and we gonna kick some.
Is that understood? That's what
we gonna do, sweethearts.
Yes, sir.
We are going to go
and get some.
Hey.
All right, people!
On the ready line!
Are you lean?
Are you mean?
[All ] Yeah! Yeah!
What are you?
Lean and mean!
Hudson!
Get on the ready line,
marine!
Get some today!
Get on the ready line!
Yo!
Move it out!
Move it out, goddamn it!
Get hot! One, two, three!
Get out, get out, get out!
Move it out, move it out,
move it out! Move it out,
move it out, move it out!
[ Barking Orders,
Indistinct ]
[ Growls ]
Absolutely badasses.
Let's pack 'em in.
Get in there!
All right! Move it!
Let's go, let's go!
One, two, three,
four, five, six!
All right.
I want combat seating.
You know your places.
Get those weapons stowed.
Let's go.
Come on.
Settle down, people.
Lock 'em in, Hudson.
Ready to get it on?
You know it!
Okay, Bishop,
let's go.
Roger.
I'm ready, man.
Ready to get it on!
Go!
[ Murmurs Of Agreement ]
[ Ferro On Headsets ]
Stand by. Cross-locking now.
Prelaunch autocycle engaged.
Primary couplers released.
Hit the internals.
Shit, man.
Confirm cross-lock
and drop stations secured.
[ Gorman ]
Affirmative.
All drop stations secured.
Stand by. Ten seconds.
Stand by to initiate
release sequencer...
on my mark.
- Five, four, three,
- We're on an express elevator
to hell, going down.
two, one, mark.
Woo-hoo!
- Switch to D.C.S. ranging.
- [ Spunkmeyer]
240, nominal to profile.
We're in the pipe,
five by five.
We're picking up
some hull ionization.
Got it.
Rough air ahead.
We're in for some chop.
[ Rumbling ]
How many drops is this
for you, Lieutenant?
Thirty-eight.
Simulated.
How many combat drops?
Uh, two...
including this one.
- Shit.
- Oh, man!
Range 014.
Turning on final.
[ Frost ] And I'm telling you,
I got a bad feeling
about this drop.
[ Crowe ] You always say that,
Frost. You always say, "I got
a bad feeling about this drop."
[ Frost ]
Okay, okay.
When we get back without you,
I'll call your folks.
[ Laughs ]
[ Beeping ]
All right.
Let's see what we can see.
Everybody online.
Looking good.
Drake, check your camera.
There seems to be
a malfunction.
That's better.
Pan it around a bit.
- Good.
- I'm ready, man. Check it out.
I am the ultimate badass.
Yeah.
That's right.
State-of-the-badass art.
You do not want to fuck with me.
Who here's runnin'?
Check it out.
[ Chuckles ]
Hey, Ripley,
don't worry.
Me and my squad of
ultimate badasses
will protect you.
Hey!
That's right.
Check it out.
Independently targeting
particle-beam phalanx.
[ Imitates Blast Noise ]
Fry halfa city
with this puppy.
We got tactical
smart missiles,
phase-plasma pulse rifles,
R.P.G.'s.
- We got sonic,
electronic ball breakers!
- [ Vasquez ] Whoo!
We got nukes, we got knives,
sharp sticks-
Knock it off, Hudson.
All right, gear up.
Two minutes, people.
Get hot.
Somebody wake up Hicks.
Coming around
for a 709er.
Terminal guidance
locked in.
Where's the damn beacon?
Oh, I see it.
That's the atmosphere
processor?
Yep, that's it.
Remarkable piece
of machinery.
Completely automated.
You know,
we manufacture those,
by the way.
[ Gorman ] Okay, Ferro.
Take us in low over
the main colony complex.
Storm shutters are sealed.
There's no visible activity.
All right. Hold at 40.
[ Ferro On Headset ] Roger.
Give me a slow circle
of the complex.
Structure seems intact.
They still have power.
Okay, Ferro.
Set down on
the landing grid.
Immediate dust off
on my clear,
then stay on station.
[ Ferro ]
Down and clear.
Ten seconds, people.
Look sharp.
All right. I want a nice,
clean dispersal this time.
Let's go!
Move it out!
Head 'em up!
First squad up on line.
Hicks, get yours in accord
and watch the rear.
Vasquez, take point.
Let's move!
Move up.
Hudson, run a bypass.
Second squad, move up.
Flanking positions.
[ Apone Over Headsets ]
Second squad on line.
[ Door Lock Clicks ]
[ Whispers ]
You set?
Go on.
Second team, move inside.
Hicks, take the upper level.
[ Apone ]
Sir, you copying this? Looks
like hits from small-arms fire.
Uh, we got some
explosives damage.
It's probably seismic
survey charges.
Are you reading this?
Keep it tight, people.
[ Gorman ]
All right. Hicks, Hudson,
use your motion trackers.
[ Clicking ]
Nothing.
Not a goddamn thing.
Quarter and search
by twos.
[ Snaps Fingers ]
Okay. Dietrich,
Frost, you're up.
[ Sniffs ]
[ Clicking Continues ]
[ Beeping ]
It's right in there.
[ High-pitched Beeping ]
Now!
- Haah! Uh-
- Good one, Hudson!
[ Hudson ] Uh, sir, uh, we have
a negative situation here.
Uh, movin' on, sir
[ Clicking ]
Wait. Wait,
tell him to-
Hicks, back up.
Pan right.
- There.
- You seeing this all right?
Looks melted.
Somebody must have bagged
one of Ripley's bad guys here.
Acid for blood.
If you like that,
you're gonna love this.
[ Hocking ]
Quit screwing around.
Second squad,
what's your status?
[ Hicks ]
Uh, we just finished our sweep.
Nobody's home.
Roger.
Sir, this place is dead.
Whatever happened here,
I think we missed it.
[ Sighs ] All right. The area's
secured. Let's go in and see
what their computer can tell us.
- Wait a minute.
It's not secure.
- The area's secured, Ripley.
First team,
head for operations.
Hudson, see if you can
get their C.P.U. on line.
Affirmative.
Hicks, meet me at
the south lock. We're coming in.
Roger.
He's comin' in.
I feel safer already.
Pendejo jerk-off.
[ Hudson On Radio ]
Sir, we got the C.P.U. on line.
No problem.
Good. Stand by
in Operations.
Okay, let's go.
Are you all right?
Yes.
Sir, they sealed off
this wing at both ends,
welded the doors
and blocked off the stairs
with heavy equipment.
[ Gorman ] Mm-hmm.
But it looks like
the barricade didn't hold.
Any bodies?
No, sir.
Last stand.
[ Drake ]
Must have been
a hell ofa fight.
Yeah, looks that way.
[ Gorman ]
All right, Drake, this way.
We should be able
to cut through the medlab
to Operations.
[ Hicks ]
Lieutenant.
Gorman.
Are those the same ones that-
Careful, Burke.
Looks like love
at first sight to me.
Oh, he likes you, Burke.
[ Chuckles ]
Two are alive.
The rest are dead.
"Surgically removed
before embryo implantation.
Subject Marachek, John J.,
died during the procedure."
They killed him
taking it off.
[ Clicking, Beeping ]
Yo, Hicks.
I think we got
something here.
Behind us.
One of us?
Apone, where are your people?
Anybody in "D" block?
[ Apone On Radio ]
Ah, that's a negative.
We're all in Operations.
Talk to me,
Frosty.
Let's keep moving, baby.
[ Crash ]
It's moving.
Which way?
It's coming
straight for us.
Straight up.
[ High-pitched Beeping ]
Fuck!
Hold up.
Ripley.
Hey. Shh.
It's all right.
Come on.
Just grab her, Corporal.
Don't be afraid. Come on.
We won't hurt you.
Shh. It's all right.
It's okay.
Come on out. Come on.
- Easy. Easy.
- I got her.
Ow! Damn!
Watch her!
She's under the grille!
Don't let her go.
Frost, get your light
up here.
Where'd she go?
Shine the light.
Here. Here.
There she is.
[ Ripley ]
Keep back. Keep back.
Don't scare her.
[ Hicks ] Grab her, man.
We're gonna lose her.
[ Ripley ] Damn it!
[ Hicks ]
Kick it out!
[ Grunts ]
Wait.
[ Clattering ]
It's okay.
It's all right.
Don't be afraid.
See?
Wait.
No, you don't.
[ Screams ]
It's okay.
You're gonna
be all right now.
[ Whimpering ]
Shh.
Easy. Easy.
It's gonna be okay.
It's all right.
You're gonna be okay.
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
Easy. Easy.
[ Whirring ]
What's her name again?
Rebecca.
Now think, Rebecca.
Concentrate.
Just start
at the beginning.
Where are your parents?
Now, look, Rebecca,
you have to try and help-
Gorman, give it a rest,
why don't you?
[ Sighs ]
Total brain lock.
Physically, she's okay.
Borderline malnutrition,
but I don't think there's
any permanent damage.
Come on.
We're wasting our time.
Try this.
It's a little
hot chocolate.
There you go.
Whoop.
That good, huh?
Uh-oh. I made
a clean spot here.
Now I've done it.
Guess l'll have to
do the whole thing.
Hard to believe
there's a little girl
under all this.
And a pretty one too.
You don't talk much,
do you?
Smoking
or nonsmoking?
Just tell me what
you're scanning for, Private.
P.D.T.s.
What?
Personal data
transmitters.
Every colonist had one
surgically implanted.
If they're
within 20 klicks,
we'll read it out here.
So far, zippo.
I don't know how you
managed to stay alive,
but you're one
brave kid, Rebecca.
[ Whispers ]
N-Newt.
- What'd you say?
- Newt.
My name's Newt.
Nobody calls me Rebecca
except my brother.
Newt?
I like that.
I'm Ripley.
It's nice to meet you.
And who is this, hmm?
Casey.
Hello, Casey.
What about your brother?
What's his name?
Timmy.
Is Timmy around here too?
Maybe hiding like you were?
Any sisters?
Mom and dad?
Newt, look at me.
Where are they?
They're dead, all right?
Can I go now?
I'm sorry, Newt.
Don't you think you'd
be safer here with us?
These people are here
to protect you.
They're soldiers.
It won't make
any difference.
[ Door Opens ]
[ Cart's Wheels Clacking ]
Need anything else?
Hello, Bishop. Do you
need anything else?
No.
That's a nice pet
you got there, Bishop.
Magnificent, isn't it?
Yo! Stop your grinnin'
and drop your linen! Found 'em.
They alive?
Unknown,
but it looks
like all of them.
Over at the processing station,
Sublevel 3,
under the main
cooling towers.
Looks like
a goddamn town meeting.
Let's saddle up, Apone.
Aye, sir.
All right. Let's go, people.
They ain't payin' us
by the hour.
Let's go.
Head 'em out!
Okay, Frost,
you're driving.
It's okay. Don't worry.
It'll be okay.
[ Gorman On Radio ] I want
a straight "V" deployment,
second team on left flank.
Advance on axial 664.
Tracker on line.
Set the "V" gain
to filter R.F. ambient.
[ Apone ]
Hudson, tracker on line.
Left and right, little buddy.
[ Clicking ]
[ Gorman ]
Forty meters in, bearing 221 ,
there should be a stairwell.
Check. Got it.
[ Gorman ]
You want Sublevel 3.
[ Apone ]
Let's go, people.
Hudson, you got the point.
Hicks, watch our tails.
Nice and easy.
Check those corners.
Watch your spacing.
[ Apone ] All right.
You heard the man.
Don't bunch up.
Stay loose.
[ Gorman ]
Uh, your transmission's
showing a lot ofbreakup.
[ Hudson ] Probably
getting some interference
from the structure.
[ Apone ]
Use those lights.
[ Gorman ]
Next one down,
and proceed on a 216.
[Apone ]
Uh, roger. That's a 216.
[ Gorman ]
I'm not making that out
too well. What is it, Hudson?
You tell me, man.
I only work here.
What is that?
I don't know.
Proceed inside.
[ Apone On Headset ]
Watch your fire
and check your targets.
Remember we're looking
for civvies in here.
[ Apone ]
Easy.
[ Hicks ]
Tighten it up, Frost.
We're getting a little thin.
[Apone ]
Nice and easy.
Looks like some sort
of secreted resin.
Yeah, but secreted
from what?
Nobody touch nothing.
Busy little
creatures, huh?
Hot as hell in here.
Yeah, man,
but it's a dry heat.
[Apone ]
Knock it off, Hudson.
Lieutenant, what do
those pulse rifles fire?
Ten millimeter
explosive-tip caseless.
Standard light
armor-piercing round.
Why?
Well, look where
your team is.
They're right under
the primary
heat exchangers.
So?
So if they fire their weapons
in there, won't they rupture
the cooling system?
- Ho, ho, ho. Yeah.
She's absolutely right.
- So? So what?
Look. This whole station is
basically a big fusion reactor.
Right?
So you're talking about
a thermonuclear explosion,
and adios, muchachos.
Oh, great. Wonderful.
Shit!
Look.
Uh... Apone.
[ Snapping Fingers ]
Look. We can't have
any firing in there.
I, uh, I want you to collect
magazines from everybody.
- Is he fuckin' crazy?
- What the hell are we supposed
to use, man, harsh language?
- Flame units only.
I want rifles slung.
- Sir, I-
Just do it, Sergeant.
And no grenades.
All right, sweethearts.
You heard the man. Pull 'em out.
Come on. Let's have 'em.
Come on, Vasquez.
Clear and lock.
Damn!
You too. Give it up, Ski.
Come on. Let's go.
Crowe, I want it now.
Give it up.
Right on, Vas.
Let's go, marine.
Give it up.
Frost, you got the duty.
Open that bag.
- Thanks a lot, Sarge.
- Hicks, cover our ass.
Head 'em out, people.
I like to keep this handy...
for close encounters.
I heard that.
[ Tracker Clicking ]
[ Gorman ]
Any movement?
Nothing. Zip.
Holy shit.
[ Ripley ]
Newt, go sit up front.
Go on! Now!
[ Apone ]
Steady, people.
Let's finish our sweep.
We're still marines,
and we got a job to do.
Keep it moving. Easy.
- Help!
- What?
Top, get over here.
We got a live one!
You're gonna be all right.
Please... k-kill me.
[ Dietrich ]
Just stay calm.
We're gonna get you outta here.
It's gonna be all right.
Give me a hand.
We gotta get her outta here.
- What is it, Dietrich?
- Convulsion!
- [ Screaming ]
- Dietrich, get back!
- Get back!
- [ Screams ]
- No!
- Frost, flamethrower.
Kill it!
Get back!
Flamethrower! Move!
[ Alien Screeches ]
- [ Groaning ]
- [ Screeching ]
[ Hissing ]
[ Tracker Beeping ]
Movement!
- What's the position?
- I can't lock in!
Talk to me, Hudson!
Multiple signals.
They're closing.
Go to infrared, people.
Look sharp!
What's happening, Apone?
Can't see anything in here.
Pull your team out,
Gorman.
I got signals.
I got readings
in front and behind.
Where, man?
I don't see shit.
He's right.
There's nothing back here.
Look, I'm telling you.
There's something moving,
and it ain't us!
- Oh, shit.
- [ Hudson ]
Tracker's off scale, man.
They're all
around us, man! Jesus!
Maybe they don't show up
on infrared at all.
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming ]
- Frost!
- [ Screams ]
Come on!
- [ Steady Beep ]
- Jesus Christ, Apone!
What is going on?
[ Hicks ]
Wierzbowski
and Crowe are down!
Dietrich, Crowe!
Sound off! Frost!
Dietrich, Frost, off the board!
Frost!
[ Man Screaming ]
Wierzbowski?
- Wierzbowski?
- [ Wierzbowski Screaming ]
[ Grunts ]
Let's rock!
[ Drake Shouting ]
[ Gunfire ]
Who's firing?
Goddamn it!
Yeah!
I ordered to hold fire.
[ Hudson ] They're coming
out of the walls!
They're coming out
of the goddamn walls!
Let's book!
[ Vasquez ]
On the right, man.
Uh, Apone,
I want you to lay down
a suppressing fire with the incinerators-
Vasquez, Drake,
hold your fire,
goddamn it!
[ Gorman ] Apone, are you
copying me? I want you
to lay down suppressing fire...
with the incinerators
and fall back by squads
to the A.P.C.
Over.
Say again,
all after "incinerator."
I said I want you to lay down
a suppressing fire with
the incinerators and fall back...
by squads to the A.P.C.
Over.
[ Gunfire ]
Hey!
[ Screaming ]
- [ Hudson ] Sarge! Sarge!
- Apone.
Talk to me. Apone?
Copy! Copy!
Talk to me, Apone.
He's gone!
Get them out of there!
Shut up!
Do it now! Hicks,
whoever's left, get-
Shut up!
Just shut up!
Goddamn it!
It's coming out of
the goddamn walls!
Where's Apone? Where's Apone?
The sarge is gone!
Let's get the fuck out of here!
Let's move it!
Let's go, marine!
Hudson? Vasquez?
Hudson, look out!
Get it!
[ Alien Screeching ]
Watch it!
Hicks.
Come on. Behind you!
Fall back!
I told them to fall back.
[ Hicks ]
Fall back, goddamn it, now!
They're cut off!
[ Hicks ]
Hudson, move your ass!
Do something!
[ Hicks ] Let's go, marine!
Fuck!
Come on.
Keep moving, baby.
Hold on, Newt.
[ Engines Revving ]
Ripley, what the hell
are you doing?
[ Tires Squealing ]
Turn around!
That's an order!
Get offme, damn it!
Goddamn it, that's an order!
You had your chance,
Gorman.
[ Tires Squealing ]
Come on!
- Come on. Let's move it!
- [ Screeches ]
[ Vasquez ] Come on!
Let's go! Let's go!
[ Hudson ] It's blocked, man.
We gotta go around!
- Open the door! Hicks!
- Drake, we are leaving!
[ Drake ]
Get them, man!
Run for it!
Shit!
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunts ]
Go! Go!
[ Vasquez ] Come on, man! Come on!
- Drake, come on!
- [ Screeches ]
- [ Screams ]
- No!
- Fire in the hole!
- [ Hicks ] He's gone!
Put it out! Put it out!
Go! Go!
- Come on. Put it out!
- Drake's coming, man!
Drake!
No, he's not!
He's gone!
Forget him!
They're in the goddamn door!
Eat this!
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Hicks ] Ripley!
Go, go, go!
[ Clatter]
It's all right!
We're clear!
[ Metal Clattering ]
Ripley, you've blown
the transaxle!
You're just
grinding metal!
Come on, ease down.
Ease down.
Ease down. Ease down.
[ Newt Coughing ]
You okay?
l'm all right.
Hudson.
Get away from me, man!
Lieutenant.
What happened
to Gorman?
I don't know.
Maybe a concussion.
But he's alive.
He's dead!
Wake up, pendejo, and then
I'm gonna kill you!
Back off.
Right now.
Fuck!
Somebody get me
a first aid kit.
Hey. Hey, look.
The sarge and Dietrich
aren't dead, man.
Their signs are real low,
but they ain't dead.
- Then we go back
in there and get them.
- Fuck that!
We don't leave our people behind—
I ain't going back in there.
You can't help them!
You can't. Right now
they're being cocooned
just like the others.
Oh, dear Lord Jesus,
this ain't happenin', man.
Damn it.
This can't be happenin', man.
This isn't happenin'!
All right. We got
seven canisters of CN-20.
I say we roll them in there
and nerve gas
the whole fucking nest.
That's worth a try,
but we don't even know
if it's gonna affect them.
Let's just bug out and call it
even. Okay? What are we
talking about this for?
I say we take off
and nuke the entire
site from orbit.
It's the only way
to be sure.
Fuckin' "A"!
Hold on.
Hold on one second.
This installation has
a substantial dollar value
attached to it.
They can bill me.
Okay, look.
This is an emotional moment
for all of us, okay?
I know that.
But let's not make
snap judgments, please.
This is clearly-
clearly an important species
we're dealing with,
and I don't think that
you or I or anybody
has the right...
- to arbitrarily
exterminate them.
- Wrong.
Yeah. Watch us.
Maybe you haven't been
keeping up on current events,
but we just got
our asses kicked, pal!
Look. I'm not blind
to what's going on,
but I cannot authorize
that kind of action.
I'm sorry.
Well, I believe
Corporal Hicks...
has authority here.
Corporal Hicks is-
This operation
is under military
jurisdiction,
and Hicks is next
in chain of command.
Am I right, Corporal?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's right.
Yeah. Look, Ripley.
Yes.
This is a multimillion-dollar
installation, okay?
He can't make
that kind of decision.
He's just a grunt.
Uh, no offense.
None taken.
Ferro, do you copy?
Standing by.
Prep for dust off.
We're gonna need
immediate evac.
Roger. On our way.
I say we take off,
nuke the site from orbit.
It's the only way to be sure.
Let's do it.
[ Wind Whistling ]
Let's go.
Pick it up, Hudson.
Pick it up, baby.
All right.
Set him down here.
Move it, Spunkmeyer.
We're rolling.
Hold on a second.
There's something-
[ Ferro ]
Just get up here.
I'm in. Ramp closing.
Spunkmeyer.
Goddamn it.
[ Door Opens ]
Well, where the fuck-
[ Hisses ]
Run!
Well, that's great.
That's just fuckin' great, man.
Now what the fuck
are we supposed to do?
We're in some
real pretty shit now, man!
Are you finished?
You all right?
I guess we're not gonna
be leaving now, right?
I'm sorry, Newt.
You don't have to be sorry.
It wasn't your fault.
That's it, man.
Game over, man!
Game over!
What the fuck
are we gonna do now?
What are we gonna do?
Maybe we could build a fire.
Sing a couple of songs, huh?
Why don't we try that?
We'd better get back
'cause it'll be dark soon,
and they mostly
come at night, mostly.
That's everything, right?
All right. This is
absolutely everything...
that we could salvage
out of the A.P.C. wreckage.
We got four pulse rifles
with about 50 rounds each.
That ain't so good.
We got, uh,
1 5 of these M-40 grenades.
Don't touch that.
Dangerous, honey.
Is that the only
flamethrower?
[ Hicks ]
Yeah. It's only half full,
but it's functional.
Got another one, it's damaged—
I don't know about that one.
But the good news-
we got four of these
robot sentries,
with display
and scanners intact.
They really kick ass.
I think they'll come in handy.
How long after
we're declared overdue
can we expect a rescue?
Seventeen days.
Seventeen days?
Hey, man, I don't wanna rain
on your parade, but we're
not gonna last 17 hours.
Those things are gonna come in
here like they did before.
They're gonna come in here-
Hudson! Hudson!
They're gonna come in here
and they're gonna get us!
This little girl
survived longer than that...
with no weapons
and no training.
Right?
Why don't you
put her in charge?
You'd better just start
dealing with it, Hudson.
Listen to me.
Hudson, just deal with it
because we need you.
And I'm sick
of your bullshit.
Now, I want you to get on
a terminal and call up
some kind of floor plan file.
Do you understand?
Construction blueprints.
I don't care.
Anything that shows
the layout of this place.
Are you listening?
Yeah.
I need to see air ducts.
I need to see
electrical access tunnels,
subbasements,
every possible way
into this complex.
- We don't have much time.
- Okay.
Okay, I'm on it.
Hudson!
- Just relax.
- [ Exhales Sharply ]
I'll be in medlab.
I'll check on Gorman,
continue my analysis.
Fine.
You do that.
So this service tunnel
must be how they're moving
back and forth.
That's right.
It moves from
the processing station...
right into
the sublevel here.
Come down on that.
Okay, come over.
Hold. Go back.
Okay, punch that in
right there.
No. It's back here.
Okay.
Well, there's
a pressure door
at this end.
Couldn't we put one of
the remote sentry units
in the tunnel and then seal that door?
Yeah, that'll work,
but we gotta figure on them
getting into the complex.
That's right,
so we repair the barricades
at these two intersections.
Right.
And weld plate steel
over these ducts...
here and here and here.
That way they can
only come at us
from these two corridors.
All right. Then we put
the other sentry units
here and here, right?
Right.
Outstanding.
Now all we need
is a deck of cards.
All right, people.
Let's move like
we got a purpose.
[ Hudson ]
Affirmative.
[ Beeping ]
Do your thing, baby.
Come on, Vasquez.
Let's get the hell outta here.
Hudson here.
"A" and "B" sentries
are in place and keyed.
Roger. Stand by.
Arming now.
Test it, Hudson.
Do it!
Fire in the hole!
Okay, great.
Let's get the hell
outta here!
We're sealing the tunnel.
Come on, baby.
[ Welder Crackling ]
For what it's worth.
Here. I want you
to put this on.
- What's it for?
- It's a locator.
Then I can find you
anywhere in the complex
on this.
[ Beeping ]
It's just
a precaution.
Thanks.
Doesn't mean we're
engaged or anything.
All right,
what's next?
[ Beeping ]
[ Door Closes ]
Last stop.
Get in.
Scoot down.
That's good.
Now, you lie here
and have a nap.
You're very tired.
I don't want to.
I have scary dreams.
Well, I bet Casey doesn't
have scary dreams.
Let's take a look.
Nope. Nothing bad
in there.
See? Maybe you could
just try to be like her, hmm?
Ripley, she doesn't
have bad dreams...
because she's just
a piece of plastic.
Right.
I'm sorry, Newt.
There.
My mommy always said
there were no monsters-
no real ones-
but there are.
Yes, there are,
aren't there?
Why do they tell
little kids that?
Most of the time
it's true.
Did one of those things
grow inside her?
I don't know, Newt.
That's the truth.
Isn't that how babies come?
I mean, people babies?
They grow inside you.
Oh, that's very different.
Did you ever
have a baby?
Yes, I did.
I had a little girl.
Where is she?
She's gone.
You mean dead.
Here.
Take this.
For luck.
There's that.
Don't go, please.
Newt, I'm gonna be
right in the next room.
And you see that camera
right up there?
I can see you
right through that camera,
all the time
to see if you're safe.
I'm not gonna
leave you, Newt.
I mean that.
That's a promise.
You promise?
I cross my heart.
- And hope to die?
- And hope to die.
[ Kisses ]
Now go to sleep,
and don't dream.
[ Laughs ]
Sneak.
[ Door Opens ]
The molecular acid oxidizes
after the creature's death,
completely neutralizing it.
Bishop, you know, that's
very interesting, but it doesn't
really get us anywhere, does it?
I'm trying to figure out
what we're dealing with here.
Let's go through it again.
They grab the colonists,
they move them over there...
and they immobilize them
to be hosts for more of these.
Which would mean that
there would have to be
a lot of these parasites, right?
One for each colonist.
That's over 100, at least.
Yes. Τhat follows.
But each one of these things
comes from an egg, right?
So who's laying
these eggs?
I'm not sure.
It must be something
we haven't seen yet.
Hey, maybe it's like
an ant hive.
Bees, man.
Bees have hives.
You know what I mean.
There's, like, one female
that runs the whole show.
Yes, the queen.
Ueah, the mama.
She's badass, man.
I mean, big.
These things ain't ants,
estúpido.
I know that.
Bishop, I want these specimens
destroyed as soon as
you're finished with them.
- Is that clear?
- Mr. Burke gave instructions...
that they were to be kept alive
in stasis for return
to the company labs.
He was very specific
about it.
Look. Those two specimens
are worth millions
to the bio-weapons division, right?
Now, if you're smart,
we can both come out
of this heroes,
and we will be
set up for life.
You're crazy, Burke.
Do you know that?
Do you really think you can get
a dangerous organism like that
past I.C.C. quarantine?
How can they impound it
if they don't
know about it?
But they will know about it,
Burke, from me.
Just like they'll know
that you were responsible
for the deaths of 157 colonists.
Wait a second.
You sent them
to that ship.
You're wrong.
I just checked
the colony log.
Directive dated 6-1 2-79,
signed Burke, Carter J.
You sent them out there,
and you didn't even warn them.
Why didn't you
warn them, Burke?
Okay, look.
What if that ship
didn't even exist?
Do you ever think about that?
I didn't know. So now
if I went and made a major
security situation out of it,
everybody steps in,
administration steps in, and
there's no exclusive rights for anybody.
Nobody wins.
So I made a decision,
and it was wrong.
It was a bad call, Ripley.
It was a bad call.
Bad call?
Right.
These people
are dead, Burke!
Don't you have any idea
what you've done here?
I'm gonna make sure
that they nail you
right to the wall for this!
You're not gonna
sleaze your way
out of this one.
Right to the wall.
Ripley. I-
You know, I expected
more from you.
I thought you'd be
smarter than this.
Well, I'm happy
to disappoint you.
[Alarm Blaring ]
- [ Hudson ]
What is it? What's going on?
- They're coming.
Where?
In the tunnel.
[Automatic Gunfire ]
Here we go. "A" and "B"
gun tracking far end.
Multiple targets.
Those ammo counters go.
"B" gun's down 50%..
Man, it's a shooting gallery
down there.
- [ Hicks ]
Sixty rounds left on "B."
- [ Beeping ]
Forty. Twenty. Ten.
"B" gun's dry.
Twenty on "A."
- Ten. Five.
- [ Steady Beep ]
That's it.
Jesus, they were
wall-to-wall in there.
[ Pounding ]
They're at
the pressure door.
Man, listen to that.
Bishop here.
I'm afraid I have
some bad news.
Well, that's a switch.
It's very pretty, Bishop,
but what are we looking for?
That's it.
Emergency venting.
Oh, that's beautiful, man.
Oh, man, that-
that just beats it all.
How long till it blows?
Four hours.
[ Groans ]
With a blast radius
of 30 kilometers,
equal to about
40 megatons.
We got problems.
[ Hudson ] I don't believe this.
I don't fucking believe this.
Vasquez,
close the shutters.
Why can't we shut it
down from here?
I'm sorry.
The crash caused
too much damage.
An overload is inevitable
at this point.
Oh, man, and I was
getting short.
Four more weeks and out.
Now l'm gonna buy it
on this rock.
It ain't half fair, man.
Hudson, give us a break!
[ Hudson ]
Four more weeks. Oh, man.
We've got to get the other
drop ship from the Sulaco.
I mean, there must be some way
of bringing it down on remote.
How? The transmitter
was on the A.P.C.
It's wasted.
I don't care how,
but we'd better think of something.
We'd better think of a way.
Think of what?
We're fucked! We're doomed!
Shut up!
Shut up! What about
the colony transmitters?
The uplink tower
down at the other end.
Why can't we use that?
No, I checked.
The hardware in between here
and there was damaged.
We can't align the dish.
Well, somebody's gonna
have to go out there,
take a portable terminal,
go out there
and patch in manually.
Oh, yeah, sure. With those
things running around?
You can count me out.
Guess we can just
count you out of everything.
I'll go.
[ Hudson ] That's right, man.
Why don't you go, man?
[ Bishop ]
I'll go.
What?
I'll go. I mean,
I'm the only one qualified
to remote pilot the ship anyway.
Yeah, right, man.
Bishop should go.
Good idea.
Believe me,
I'd prefer not to.
I may be synthetic,
but I'm not stupid.
[ Ripley]
How long?
This conduit runs almost
to the uplink assembly-
1 80 meters.
Say 40 minutes
to crawl down there-
[ Ripley ] Right.
An hour to patch in
and align the antenna.
Thirty minutes
to prep the ship,
and about 50 minutes
flight time.
It's gonna be close.
Good luck.
See you soon.
Watch your fingers.
[ Grunts ]
Vaya con Dios, man.
This is unbelievable.
Twenty meters and closing.
Fifteen.
How many?
[ Hicks ]
Can't tell. Lots.
"D" gun's down 50%..
[Aliens Screeching ]
"C" gun's right behind it.
[ Hudson ]
Stopping them.
It ain't stopping them.
- [ Hicks ] 150 rounds on "D."
- [ Hudson ]
Come on. Come on, baby.
[ Hicks ]
Hundred rounds.
[ Hudson ]
Come on! Come on!
[ Beeping ]
"D" gun's down to 20.
Ten.
Damn it!
Wait! They're retreating.
[ Ripley ]
The guns stopped them.
You're right.
Next time they walk
right up and knock.
Yeah, but they don't
know that.
They're probably looking
for other ways to get in.
That'll take 'em a while.
Maybe we got 'em
demoralized.
Shut up!
I want you two
walking perimeter.
Move!
Hey, listen.
We're all
in strung-out shape,
but stay frosty
and alert.
We can't afford to let
one of those bastards in here.
All right.
Vámonos.
How long's it been
since you got any sleep?
Twenty-four hours?
Hicks, I'm not
gonna end up
like those others.
You'll take care
of it, won't you?
If it comes to that,
I'll do us both.
Listen, let's just make sure
it doesn't come to that.
All right?
All right.
Hey, I want to introduce you
to a personal friend of mine.
This is an M-41A
pulse rifle, 10 millimeter,
with an over-and-under
30 millimeter
pump-action grenade launcher.
Feel the weight.
Okay, what do I do?
Okay, pull it in
tight here.
Right.
Uh-huh.
Lean into it.
Mm-hmm.
All right.
Now, it will kick some.
When the counter
reads zero here, you-
I press this up?
That's right.
Get another one in quick.
Slap it in hard.
Right.
And you're ready
to rock and roll.
What's this?
That's the grenade
launcher.
I don't think you
want to mess with that.
You started this.
Show me everything.
I can handle myself.
Yeah, I noticed.
How do you feel?
All right, I guess.
One hell of a hangover.
Look, Ripley,
I just want-
Forget it.
Excuse me.
[ Newt Groaning ]
Shh, shh, shh, shh, shh.
It's okay. It's okay.
[ Whispering ]
Newt, wake up.
Wha-
Be quiet.
We're in trouble.
- No!
- [ Screams ]
Move, Newt!
[ Both Grunting ]
Hey!
[ No Audio ]
Help! Help!
Hicks!
Somebody!
[ Hicks ]
Say again, Bishop.
You've got it
into auto-refuel mode,
and it's sequencing right?
[ Bishop On Radio ]
That's right.
Okay, good. Stay on it.
[ Indistinct ]
Get back to me when you've
activated the launch cycle.
Roger.
He's at the uplink tower.
Good.
Terrific.
[ Ripley ]
Hicks! Hicks! Hicks!
[ Newt ] Help!
- Help! Help!
- Hicks, help us!
- Break the glass!
Break it. Break it.
- Yes.
I'll try.
[ Scurrying ]
[ Clinking ]
Ripley, I'm scared.
Me too.
Stay here.
[Alarm Blaring ]
It's the medlab. Hudson!
Vasquez, meet me in medlab.
We got a fire.
[ Hudson On Radio ]
We're on our way.
They're coming, Newt.
[ Screaming ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Screaming Continues ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
Shoot it out!
- Hudson!
- Jesus.
[ Gasping ]
Christ, kid, look out!
Fucking die.
Over there! Ready?
Yeah! Yeah!
[ Hicks ]
Now!
Hudson?
Yeah. All clear.
Nailed the other one.
lt's history, man.
[ Coughing ]
Jesus.
Burke-
[ Coughs ]
It was Burke.
I say we grease this rat-fuck
son of a bitch right now.
Just doesn't make
any goddamn sense.
He figured that
he could get an alien
back through quarantine...
if one of us
was impregnated-
whatever you call it-
and then frozen
for the trip home.
Nobody would know
about the embryos
we were carrying-
me and Newt.
Wait a minute, now.
We'd all know.
Yes. The only way
he could do it...
is if he sabotaged certain
freezers on the way home.
Namely yours.
Then he could
jettison the bodies
and make up any story he liked.
Fuck! He's dead.
You're dog meat, pal.
This is so nuts.
I mean, listen-
Listen to what you're saying.
It's paranoid delusion.
It's really sad.
It's pathetic.
You know, Burke, I don't know
which species is worse.
You don't see them
fucking each other over
for a goddamn percentage.
All right.
We waste him. No offense.
No! He's gotta go back-
They cut the power.
What do you mean,
they cut the power?
How could they cut the power, man?
They're animals.
I want you two with trackers,
checking the corridors! Move!
[ Ripley ]
Gorman, watch Burke!
I got him.
Newt, stay close.
I'll go this side.
You do that, man.
[ Tracker Clicking ]
Anything?
[ Hudson ]
There's something.
[ Beeping ]
It's inside the complex.
You're just reading me.
No, no, it ain't you.
They're inside-
inside the perimeter.
They're in here.
[ Ripley ]
Hudson, stay cool!
Vasquez?
[ Clicking ]
[ Beeping ]
Hudson may be right.
Get back, both of you!
[ Hudson ]
The signal's weird.
Must be some interference
or something.
There's movement
all over the place!
Get back to Operations.
It's game time.
Newt.
Seal the door.
Hurry!
Come on! Come on!
Come on! Get back!
Work fast.
Cover your eyes, Newt.
Don't look at the light.
Movement. Signal's clean.
Range, 20 meters.
They found a way in,
something we missed.
We didn't miss anything.
Eighteen.
Seventeen meters.
Something under the floor,
not in the plans.
I don't know.
- Fifteen meters.
- Ripley!
- Definitely inside
the barricades.
- Let's go.
Thirteen meters.
That's right
outside the door.
Hicks, Vasquez, get back!
This is a big fucking signal.
- How you doing, Vasquez?
Talk to me.
- Almost there.
That's it.
Twelve meters. Eleven.
[ High-pitched Beeping ]
- Ten.
- Then they're right on us.
- Nine meters.
- Remember- short,
controlled bursts.
Eight meters.
Seven.
- Six.
- It can't be.
That's inside the room.
- It's reading right, man. Look!
- Well, you're not reading
it right.
[ Hudson ]
Five meters, man.
Four. What the hell?
[ Beeping Continues ]
Oh, my God.
Oh, sh-
Give me the light.
[ Shouting ]
There they go!
Over there! Get them!
- [ Aliens Shrieking ]
- Come on! Get them!
Do something, Gorman!
[ Hudson ] Get them! Look out!
There's more of them!
Medical!
Get to Medical!
Do it! Now!
[ Hicks ]
Hudson, look out!
Look out!
[ Shouts, Screams ]
Now!
Burke!
Open this door!
Burke! Open it!
[ Shouting ]
Go! Fall back!
- Go!
- [ Shouting ]
- Die, motherfucker!
- Burke!
Hudson! Hudson!
Motherfucker! Come on!
Come on! Come and get it, baby!
Come on!
I don't got all day!
Come on! Come on!
Come on, you bastard!
Come on! You too!
Oh, you want some of this?
[ Shrieking Continues ]
Fuck you!
[ Screams ]
Fuck you! Hicks!
- Hudson!
- [ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
Come on.
Let's go!
It's locked!
- Got it! Let's go! Let's go!
- Go! Go!
- Move, Gorman!
- Seal it!
Burke! Goddamn you!
Open this door!
[ Gasps ]
- [ Hissing ]
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Screams ]
- [ Hicks ]
Get back!
- Hurry up.
- Gorman, get out of the way!
Ripley, this way!
What-
Wait. Get behind me.
Whatever you're gonna do,
do it fast!
Hicks!
Go!
Come on. Let's go.
Move!
Which way is it to
the landing field from here?
This way.
[Aliens Shrieking ]
[ Newt ]
Go right.
This way. This way.
- Which way?
- Straight ahead and left.
Bishop, do you read me?
Come in. Over.
[ Bishop ]
The ship is on its way.
E.T.A., 16 minutes.
Stand by there.
We're on our way.
- Which way now?
- That way.
No, wait. This way.
You sure?
Vasquez, move!
Right up here.
It's just up here.
Hicks!
We're almost there.
Newt, wait! Newt!
[ Shrieking ]
[ Shouts ]
[ Screams ]
Vasquez!
- [ Grunting ]
- Go!
[ Groaning ]
Oh, no!
[ Pounding ]
Newt.
Up there. There's a shortcut
across the roof.
Hicks.
[ Clicking ]
[Aliens Hissing ]
You always were
an asshole, Gorman.
- [ Ripley Grunts ]
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Ripley]
Newt! God!
- Ripley!
Newt!
Hicks! Hicks, get her!
Hurry!
[ Gasping ]
- Hold on, Newt!
- I'm slipping!
- Don't let go.
- Ripley!
- Hold on. Gotcha!
- Help!
- I gotcha.
- [ Fabric Tearing ]
- [ Screaming ]
- Newt!
[ Screaming Continues ]
No!
Come on.
We can find her with this.
[ Beeping ]
- Stay where you are, Newt.
- Ripley!
- We're coming.
- [ Beeping Continues ]
Ripley!
[ Beeping Speed Increases ]
This way.
She's close.
Newt!
Ripley!
Where are you?
Can you hear me?
Newt!
Here!
I'm here!
Where?
Newt, are you okay?
[ Grunts ]
We'll have to cut it.
Climb down, honey.
We've gotta cut through.
Newt?
Now, don't move.
Stay very still.
Okay.
We're almost there.
Hang in there, okay?
[ Beeping ]
[ High-pitched Beeping ]
Hicks. Hurry.
I know.
I know!
I mean it!
[ Beeping Continues ]
Newt? Newt,
just stay still.
- [ Screams ]
- Almost there.
No!
Newt!
[ Grunts ]
No! No!
No! No! No!
Let's go.
No! No!
They don't kill you!
They- They don't kill you!
They-
She's alive!
All right.
I believe you.
She's alive.
We've got to go. Now!
[ Ripley ]
Go!
[ High-pitched Beeping ]
- [ Screams ]
- [ Shrieking ]
[ Groaning ]
Get it off!
Hicks.
[ Groaning Continues ]
Get it off!
[ Coughing ]
[ Bell Dings ]
[ Groaning, Coughing
Continue ]
Here.
Go.
Come on.
You can make it.
[ Beeping ]
Bishop, how much time?
Plenty.
Twenty-six minutes.
We're not leaving.
We're not?
[ Beeping ]
Ripley-
I don't wanna hear about it, Bishop.
She's alive. There's still time.
In 19 minutes, this area
is gonna be a cloud of vapor
the size of Nebraska.
Hicks,
don't let him leave.
We ain't going anywhere.
[ Beeping Continues ]
See you, Hicks.
Dwayne.
It's Dwayne.
Ellen.
Don't be gone long, Ellen.
[Alarm Blaring ]
[ Computer Voice ]
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
You now have 15 minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
You now have 14 minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
[ Beeping Continues ]
[ Beeping Speed Increases ]
[ Rapid Beeping ]
[ Sobs ]
Oh.
[ Grunting ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
- Ripley! Ripley!
- Newt.
Grab on to me!
Hold on!
[ Hissing ]
[ Screeching ]
[ Screeching Stops ]
[ Screeching Continues ]
[ Grunting ]
Let's go!
Behind us!
[Alarm Blaring ]
[ Screeching ]
[Alarm Continues ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Computer Voice ]
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
You now have four minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
[ Pounding Buttons ]
[ Screeching, Distant ]
Come on, goddamn it!
Hold on to me!
[ Hissing ]
[ Screeching ]
Attention. Emergency.
All personnel
must evacuate immediately.
You now have two minutes...
to reach minimum safe distance.
No.
Bishop, goddamn you!
Close your eyes, baby.
Look!
[ Screeching ]
Come on! Come on!
Punch it, Bishop!
[ Explosion ]
It's okay.
We're okay.
Hey.
We made it.
I knew you'd come.
He's gonna be all right.
He's just out.
I had to give him another shot
for the pain.
We need a stretcher
to carry him up to Medical.
Okay.
I'm sorry if I scared you.
That platform wasjust
becoming too unstable.
I had to circle and hope
that things didn't get
too rough to take you off.
Bishop, you did okay.
- I did?
- Oh, yeah.
[ Sizzling ]
[ Gasps ]
Go! Move!
No! Here! Here!
- [ Hissing ]
- Run!
Here!
[ Pounding ]
[ Footsteps Clanging ]
- [ Hissing ]
- [ Yelps ]
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Door Rattling ]
Get away from her,
you bitch!
[ Hisses ]
[ Screeches ]
- [ Shouts ]
- [ Screeching ]
- [ Hisses ]
- Come on! Come on!
[ Screeching ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Shouts ]
[ Screaming ]
Ripley!
[ Alarm Blaring ]
[ Grunts ]
- [ Screaming ]
- [ Shouting ]
[ Shouting ]
- [ Screams ]
- [ Screeching ]
[ Screaming ]
Bishop!
Mommy.
Oh, God!
Not bad for a h-human.
Are we gonna sleep
all the way home?
All the way home.
Can I dream?
Yes, honey.
I think we both can.
[ Chuckles ]
Sleep tight.
Affirmative.
[ Scurrying ]
English - US - PSDH
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player