Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
[ Rhythmic Droning ]
[ Rattling ]
[ Humming ]
[ Electronic Chittering ]
[ Clacking ]
[ Distorted Computer Noises ]
[ Noises Stop ]
[ Chattering, Indistinct ]
The food is terrible.
Worst shit
I've ever seen, man.
[ Parker ]
What you say?
You got any biscuits over there?
[ Ripley ]
I keep seeing corn bread.
- I am cold.
- Still with us, Brett?
- Right.
- Oh, I feel dead.
Anybody ever tell you
you look dead, man?
[ Mouthing Words ]
[ Parker ]
Oh, yeah, right.
Now, I just
forgot something, man.
Before we dock,
I think we oughta discuss
the bonus situation.
Right.
Brett and I,
we think we oughta-
- We deserve full shares, right, baby?
- You see, Mr. Parker and I...
feel that the bonus situation
has never been on
an equitable level.
Well, you'll get
what you're contracted for
like everybody else.
Yes, but everybody else
gets more than us.
[ Monitor Beeping ]
Dallas, Mother
wants to talk to you.
Huh? Yeah, I saw it.
Yellow light's
for my eyes only.
Okay, get dressed, huh?
Parker, come on.
Can I finish my coffee?
Thank you.
It's the only thing
good on this ship.
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ Buzzes ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Clacking ]
[ Electronic Chittering ]
[ Dallas ]
Morning, Mother.
[ Beeping, Whirring ]
[ Voice Over Radio, Indistinct ]
- Right.
- Okay.
Plug us in.
Thank you.
- Where's Earth?
- You should know.
It's not our system.
Scan.
[ Sighs ]
I can't believe this.
Contact Traffic Control.
[ Ripley ] This is
commercial towing vehicle
Nostromo out of the Solomons.
Registration number:
1-8-0-niner-2-4-6-0-niner.
Calling Antarctica
Traffic Control.
Can you read me? Over.
Commercial towing vehicle
Nostromo out of the Solomons,
registration number-
Nothing.
[ Kane ]
Keep trying.
Calling Antarctica
Traffic Control. Do you
read me, Antarctica? Over.
I found it.
Just short of Zeta II Reticuli.
[ Ripley Chattering On Radio ]
We haven't reached
the outer rim yet.
That's hard to believe.
[ Lambert ]
What the hell
are we doing out here?
I don't know.
What the hell are you talking about?
- That's not our system.
- I know that.
[ Loud Rumbling ]
[ Parker ] Do you ever notice
how they never come down here?
I mean, this is where
the work is, right?
Well, it's the same damn reason
we get a half share
to their one.
Our time is their time.
That's the way they see it.
No, but- Listen, man.
Same old shit, man.
I think I know why they
don't come down here.
It's because of you.
You don't have no personality.
Wonder what they want now.
What's going on down here?
Um, you happen to be
in my seat. Can I have it?
Yes, of course.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
[ Wiping ]
[ Parker ]
What's happenin' now, baby?
Well, some of you
may have figured out
we're not home yet.
- We're only halfway there.
- What?
Mother's interrupted
the course of our journey.
Why?
Yeah.
She's programmed to do that
should certain conditions arise.
They have.
[ Ripley ]
Like what?
It seems she has...
intercepted a transmission
of unknown origin.
She got us up to check it out.
A transmission?
Out here?
Yeah.
What kind of a transmission?
Acoustical beacon.
It repeats at intervals
of 12 seconds.
S.O.S.?
I don't know.
Human?
Unknown.
[ Brett ]
Well, so what?
[ Kane ]
We are obligated
under section eight-
I hate to bring this up,
but, uh,
this is a commercial ship,
not a rescue ship.
Right.
And it's not in my contract
to do this kind of duty.
And what about the money?
If you wanna give me some money,
I'll be happy to oblige.
The man's right.
Let's go over
the bonus situation.
- I'm sorry. Can I say something?
- Let's talk about the bonus more.
There is a clause
in the contract
which specifically states...
any systematized transmission
indicating a possible
intelligent origin...
must be investigated.
I don't wanna hear it.
We don't know
if it's intelligent.
I wanna go home and party.
Parker, will you
just listen to the man?
On penalty of
total forfeiture of shares.
No money.
You got that?
- [ Chuckling ]
Well, yeah.
- All right, we're going in.
Yeah.
We're goin' in,
aren't we?
[ Clears Throat ]
Can we all hear that,
Lambert?
[ Beeping ]
[ Electronic Pulsing ]
[ Pulsing Continues ]
[ Scoffs ]
Good God.
Doesn't sound like
any radio signal
I've heard.
Maybe it's a voice.
Well, we'll soon know.
Can you hone in
on that?
What was the, uh,
position?
6550-99.
[ Beeping ]
[ Clacking ]
All right.
It found the quadrant.
Ascension: six minutes,
20 seconds.
Declination: 39 degrees,
two seconds.
Okay. Put that
on the screen for me.
[ Lambert ]
All right.
Well, that's it.
It's a planetoid.
1200 kilometers.
It's tiny.
Any rotation?
[ Beeping ]
[ Lambert ]
About two hours.
What about gravity?
Point eight-six.
You can walk on it.
[ Lambert Over Radio ]
Approaching orbital apogee.
Mark 12, 11-
Equatorial orbit nailed.
[ Lambert ]
Nine, eight seconds
on descent.
[ Kane ] Grids energized.
Fields focused.
Five. Four-
[ Dallas, Indistinct ]
- D.O.R.'s on line.
- How's the status on the lifters?
Give me an A.C.
pressure reading.
Forty-eight seconds
and counting.
[ Ripley Over Radio ]
SR-1stable.
Prepare to disengage
from platform.
[ Lambert ]
Mark, 20 seconds.
Eighteen, 17-
Twelve, 11, 10,
nine, eight, seven,
six, five, four,
three, two, one, lock.
Disengage.
[ Ripley ]
Umbilicus clear.
Money's safe.
Let's take her down.
[ Parker ]
Nine, eight, seven-
[ Kane ]
Roll 92 degrees port yaw.
[ Ripley ]
Prime to port.
Prime ventral.
Prime dorsal.
[ Kane ]
Down a degree.
[ Lambert ]
39,000 meters.
[ Dallas Over Radio,
Indistinct ]
[ Ripley ]
Turbulence.
[ Voices Over Radio
Continue ]
Locked and floating.
You can drop us anytime now.
We'll catch you.
Inertial damping's going off.
Hold on, people.
There's gonna be a little bump.
[ Metal Creaking Loudly ]
What the hell was that?
Pressure drop in intake three.
Must've lost a shield.
Let's go with it.
[ Voices Over Radio
Continue ]
[ Grunts ]
Dropping off now.
Still dropping.
Here we are.
We've got it.
Take her down.
Navigation lights on.
[ Ash ]
We've got 5-3 still out.
No problem. Just down 11%.
Grid status okay.
[ Lambert ]
Nine,
eight, seven, six,
five, four, three,
two, one.
Kill drive engines.
[ Alarm Blaring ]
What the hell happened?
Somebody give me
a straight answer!
- Is the hull breached?
- I don't see anything.
We've still got pressure.
- Hit the screen.
- Right.
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Parker Over Radio ]
Secondary load sharing unit...
is out.
Three to four cells
are gone.
Is that it?
No, hold on.
We can't fix it
out here anyway,
and we need to reroute...
a couple of these ducts,
wouldn't you say, Brett?
Dry dock time.
Dry dock.
Tell her we need to dry-dock.
Look, we couldn't fix it
out here anyway.
We gotta reroute
all these ducts,
and in order to do that
we've got to dry-dock.
[ Sighs ]
What else?
[ Parker Over Radio ]
Some fragments kicked up,
and we've got to
clean it all out
and repressurize it.
[ Ripley Over Radio ]
How long before
we're functional?
Look, what is- What-
It's 17 hours, tell her.
At least 25 hours.
Yeah.
[ Ripley ]
Get started on the floor panel.
I'll be right down.
What the hell's
she comin' down here for?
She better stay
the fuck out of my way,
I'll tell you that.
I'd like to see
what she's gonna do
when she gets here.
[ Wind Howling ]
Any response yet?
[ Ash ]
No. Absolutely nothing.
Except
the same transmission
every 12 seconds.
All the other channels
are dead.
[ Clicks Switch ]
Kick on the floods.
We can't go anywhere
in this.
Mmm.
Well, Mother says
the sun's coming up
in 20 minutes.
How far are we from
the source of transmission?
Uh, northeast.
Just under 2,000 meters.
Walking distance?
[ Laughs ]
Well-
Can you give me
an atmospheric?
Yes.
[ Ash ]
Oh.
It's almost primordial.
There's inert nitrogen,
high concentration
of carbon dioxide crystals,
methane.
I'm working on
the trace elements.
Anything else?
Yes.
It's...
rock, lava base,
and deep cold.
Well below the line.
Mm-hmm.
[ Kane ]
I'll volunteer to be in
the first group to go out.
[ Dallas ]
Yeah, that figures.
You too, Lambert.
Swell.
[ Dallas ] Better break
out the weapons.
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Lambert ]
I can't see a goddamn thing.
[ Dallas ]
Ash, are you receiving?
[ Voices Over Radio,
Indistinct ]
[ Mouths Words ]
[ Ash ]
Good contact on my board.
[ Dallas Over Monitor ]
Clear and free.
Keep the line open. Let's go.
Hey, Ripley.
Hey, Ripley,
I wanna ask you a question.
If they find what they're
lookin' for out there, does
that mean we get full shares?
Don't worry, Parker.
You'll get whatever's
coming to you.
Look, I'm not gonna do
any more work...
till we get this
straightened out.
Brett,
you're guaranteed by law
to get a share.
[ Parker ] What?
- Why don't you just fuck off.
- What?
[ Brett ]
What'd you say, Rip?
If you have any trouble,
I'll be on the bridge.
[ Parker ]
Hey, Ripley, come back here!
[ Chuckling ]
Son of a bitch.
What's the matter?
[ Lambert ]
Can't see a goddamn thing.
[ Kane ]
Quit griping.
I like griping.
[ Dallas ]
Come on. Knock it off.
[ Clacking ]
[ Respirators Hissing ]
Ash,
can you see this?
Yes, I can.
I've never seen
anything like it.
[ Dallas ]
Very bizarre.
[ Kane ]
You said it.
[ Dallas ]
All right.
Moving on to second...
position.
[ Lambert ]
What is it?
Let's get out of here.
[ Kane ]
We've got this far.
We must go on.
We have to go on.
Will you say that again?
Shit.
[ Dallas ]
Ash, as you can see,
it's kind of hard to describe.
I'm going back to the console.
[ Voices Continue Over Monitor,
Distorted ]
[ Dallas, Faint ]
Seems to be solid.
To walk-
You can on it.
[ Dallas Continues,
Voice Distorted ]
Indistinct ]
Dallas?
[ Respirators Hissing ]
Come on down here.
Something different down here.
I don't know
what it is, but-
See if we can get up that wall.
If we can get up that wall,
we can find out.
Amazing.
[ Dallas ]
Alien life-form.
Looks like it's been dead
a long time.
Fossilized.
Looks like it's grown
out of the chair.
Bones are bent outward,
like he exploded from inside.
[ Lambert ]
Wonder what happened
to the rest of the crew.
Let's get the hell out of here.
Hey, Dallas, Lambert,
come on over here.
Come on.
What do you got?
See what you make of this.
[ Clicks Switch ]
Ash.
That transmission-
Mother's deciphered part of it.
It doesn't look like an S.O.S.
What is it, then?
Well, I-
It looks like a warning.
I'm gonna go out after them.
What's the point?
I mean, by the time
it takes to get there,
you'll-
they'll know if it's
a warning or not, yes?
[ Clicks Switch ]
[ Exhales Deeply ]
[ Dallas ]
You okay down there?
Can you see anything?
Uh... a cave.
A ca- A cave of some sort.
But l-
Well, I don't know,
but it's like
the goddamn tropics in here.
What the hell is this?
The cave is
completely enclosed,
and it's full of...
leathery objects,
like eggs or something.
[ High-pitched Humming ]
There's a layer of mist...
[ High-pitched Tone ]
just covering the eggs
that reacts when broken.
[ Dallas Over Radio ]
Kane? You all right?
I'm okay.
All right.
I just slipped.
Appears to be
completely sealed.
[ Hisses ]
Wait a minute.
There's movement.
It seems to have life.
Organic life.
[ Screeching ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Computer Clacking ]
[ Dallas Over Radio ]
You there, Ripley?
I'm right here.
[ Beeping ]
Okay, Ripley, I'm at
the inner lock hatch now.
Right.
Ripley.
We're clean. Let us in.
Right here.
- What happened to Kane?
- Something has
attached itself to him.
- We have to get him
to the infirmary right away.
- What kind of thing?
I need a clear definition.
An organism.
Open the hatch.
Wait a minute.
If we let it in,
the ship could be infected.
You know
the quarantine procedure-
24 hours for decontamination.
He could die in 24 hours.
Open the hatch.
Listen to me.
If we break quarantine,
we could all die.
Look, would you open
the goddamn hatch?
We have to get him inside.
No. I can't do that.
And if you
were in my position,
you'd do the same.
Ripley, this is an order.
Open that hatch right now.
Do you hear me?
Yes.
Ripley, this is an order!
Do you hear me?
Yes, I read you.
The answer is negative.
Inner hatch opened.
[ Whirring ]
My God.
What the hell is that?
Jesus Christ.
What is that, man?
Hey, how the hell
is he breathing?
Is he still alive
or what?
Why don't
you guys
freeze him?
How come
they don't
freeze him?
What's going on
in there?
What the fuck
is going on?
You bitch!
Jesus Christ!
Hey! Hey!
You would've
left us out there.
Break it up.
[ Dallas ]
Ripley, when I give an order,
I expect to be obeyed.
Even if it's
against the law?
You're goddamn right!
Maybe she has a point.
Who the hell knows what that thing is.
How are we gonna
get that off him?
get it off?
I'm gonna get some instruments.
My God.
Right.
I'll make an incision here.
Try and remove
one of the digitals from-
You're gonna do what?
Finger. I'm gonna try
and get his finger off.
Just a minute.
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
No, that's not- It's tearing
his scalp.
I know!
It's not coming off
without tearing his face
off with it.
We'll have to take
a look at him inside.
Right.
How come
they don't freeze him?
[ Parker Shouting ]
How come you guys
don't freeze him?
All right, you can
take your mask off.
- What's it got down his throat?
- I would suggest
it's feeding him oxygen.
Paralyzes him,
puts him in a coma,
then keeps him alive.
Now what the hell is that?
We gotta
get it off of him.
Just a minute.
I mean,
let's not be too hasty.
We don't know anything
about...
it.
Now, we're assuming
it's feeding him oxygen.
If we remove it,
it could kill him.
I'm willing to take that chance.
Let's cut it off him now.
You'll take responsibility?
Yes, I'll take responsibility.
Get him out of there.
[ Dallas ]
Where do you wanna do this?
We'll make an incision
just below the knuckle there.
Right here.
Stand by.
[ Whirring ]
[ Ash ]
Good God!
[ Dallas ]
That crap's gonna
eat through the hull.
That thing's gonna eat
through the goddamn hull.
Come on!
What's going on?
This way.
Next deck.
- [ Sizzling ]
- [ Parker ]
There it is.
Don't get under it!
Don't get under it.
Looks like it's stopping.
Take a look at this,
man.
Yeah.
Brett, give me-
What do you got, a pen there?
Give it to me, quick.
Come on! Come on!
[ Brett ]
Don't get any on your arm.
It stopped.
Don't see anything
like that except, uh,
molecular acid.
It must be using it
for blood.
It's got a wonderful
defense mechanism.
You don't dare kill it.
What about Kane?
- Here's your pen back.
- [ Brett ]
What do we do now?
Leave Kane to Ash.
You get back to work.
Well, what-
[ Electrical Crackling ]
Okay.
Try it.
[ Motor Cranking ]
Damn it.
I thought sure
that was it.
Try it again.
[ Cranking ]
I feel like I've been
in this place a month.
We shouldn't have
landed in this place
in the first place.
Shouldn't have landed
on this damn ball,
I know that.
Well, the sooner we patch this
thing up and get out of here,
the sooner we can go home.
This place
gives me the creeps.
[ Ripley ]
That's amazing. What is it?
Ah, yes, it is.
Um-
I don't know yet.
[ Coughs ]
Did you want something?
Yes. I, uh-
I'd like to have a little talk.
How's, uh- How's Kane?
He's holding.
No changes.
And, uh,
our guest?
Well-
Hmm?
Well, as I said,
I'm still...
collating, actually,
but, uh,
I have confirmed
that he's got an outer layer
of protein polysaccharides.
He has a funny habit
of shedding his cells...
and replacing them with...
polarized silicon,
which gives him
a prolonged resistance...
to adverse
environmental conditions.
Is that enough for you?
That's plenty.
What does it mean?
Please don't do that.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Well, it's
an interesting combination
of elements,
making him
a tough little son of a bitch.
And you let him in.
I was obeying
a direct order, remember?
Ash, when Dallas and Kane
are off the ship,
I'm senior officer.
Oh, yes. I forgot.
You also forgot
the science division's
basic quarantine law.
No, that I didn't forget.
Oh, I see.
You just broke it.
Huh?
Look, what would you
have done with Kane?
Hmm?
You knew
his only chance of survival
was to get him in here.
Unfortunately,
by breaking quarantine,
you risk everybody's life.
Maybe I should've
left him outside.
Maybe I've jeopardized
the rest of us, but it was
a risk I was willing to take.
That's a pretty big risk...
for a science officer.
It's, uh, not exactly
out of the manual, is it?
I do take my responsibilities
as seriously as you, you know.
You do your job...
and let me do mine, yes?
[ Wind Swirling ]
♪♪ [ Classical ]
[ Ripley ]
Where's Dallas?
[ Ash ] In the shuttle.
♪♪ [ Continues ]
[ Beep ]
[ Clicks Switch ]
Dallas.
[ Ash ] I think you should
have a look at Kane.
Why?
Something's happened.
Serious?
lnteresting.
[ Clicks Switch ]
♪♪ [ Stops ]
Ripley, meet me
in the infirmary right away.
[ Ripley ]
Where is it?
[ Ash ]
Well, I don't know. I mean,
we ought to try and find it.
[ Dallas ]
Yeah, let's check it.
[ Slow Breaths ]
Dallas,
please be careful.
[ Loud Crash ]
[ Gasps ]
Sorry.
No, not in the corner.
Psst. Have one of these.
Just in case.
Kane? Dallas?
[ Screams ]
You okay?
I didn't see it.
Was it in the overhead?
What? It was
up there somewhere.
My God.
[ Dallas ]
Cover up the damn thing!
[ Ash ] Wait.
That's alive!
That's a reflex action.
Well, we've gotta
have a look at this.
Excuse me.
[ Ash ] Seems dead enough.
[ Ripley ] Well, good.
Let's get rid of it.
Ripley, for God's sake,
this is the first time
that we've encountered
a species like this.
It has to go back.
All sorts of tests
have to be made.
Ash, are you kidding?
This thing bled acid.
Who knows what it's
gonna do when it's dead.
Think it's safe to assume
it isn't a zombie.
Dallas, it has to go back.
Well, I'd soon...
as not burn it at the stake,
but you're the science officer.
It's your decision, Ash.
Dallas.
How come
I've got to change my mind?
The decision's been made.
I'm not trying
to change your mind, Dallas.
I just want you to listen-
Will you listen to-
[ Groans ]
Just tell me how
you can leave that kind
of decision to him.
Look, I just run the ship.
Anything that has to do
with the science division,
Ash has the final word.
-How does that happen?
-It happens, my dear, because that's
what the company wants to happen.
Since when is that
standard procedure?
Standard procedure
is to do what the hell
they tell you to do.
What's happening with
the repairs? How's it going?
They're pretty much finished now.
Why the hell
didn't you tell me so?
- Because there's still
some things left to do.
- Like what?
Well, we're blind
on "B" and "C" decks.
The reserve power
system's blown-
That's a bunch of horseshit.
We can take off without that.
Yeah, we can.
You think that's a good idea?
Look, I just wanna get
the hell out of here,
all right?
[ Engines Roaring ]
Dust in the intakes again.
Number two's overheating.
Spit on it for two minutes,
would you, for Christ's sake?
[ Ripley ]
We're hot.
We're getting hotter.
Engine room,
red clip status?
One kilometer on ascension.
[ Ripley ]
Engage artificial gravity.
Engaged.
I'm altering the vector now.
[ Dallas ]
Inhibit C.N.G. control.
Struts retract.
[ Parker ]
Struts retracted.
[ Lambert ]
Max stress to fifth overload.
[ Dallas ]
Ease it back.
She's great. Beautiful.
Walk in the park.
When we fix something,
we stay fixed.
Don't we, Brett baby?
[ Brett ]
Right.
[ Parker ]
What I think we should do
is just freeze him.
If he's got a disease,
why don't we stop it
where it is?
- He can always get to a doctor
when we get back home.
- Right.
Whenever he says anything,
you say "right," Brett.
You know that?
Right.
[ Sighs ]
Parker, what do you think?
Your staffjust follows you
around, says "right."
- Just like a regular parrot.
- Yeah. Shape up.
- What are you,
some kind of parrot?
- Right.
Come on. Knock it off!
Kane's gonna have to
go into quarantine.
That's it.
Yes, and so will we.
Well, how about
a little something
to lower your spirits?
Thrill me,
will you, please?
Well, according
to my calculations,
based on time spent getting
to and from the planet-
Just give me the short version.
How far to Earth?
Ten months.
Oh, God.
Great.
[ Monitor Buzzes ]
Yes.
[ Ash ]
Dallas, I think
you should come and see Kane.
Has his condition changed?
It's simpler if you'd just
come and see him.
[ Ripley ]
We're on our way.
Right.
[ Laughter ]
[ Lambert ]
How are you doing?
[ Coughs ]
Thank you.
How you doin'?
Um, terrific.
Next silly question.
[ Laughing ]
Oh, thank you.
Do you remember anything
about the planet?
What's the last thing
you do remember?
Huh?
[ Sighs ]
I remember some...
horrible dream about...
smothering.
And-
And- Anyway,
where are we?
Right here.
We're on our way home.
Back to the old
freezerinos.
Could I have something to eat
before we go back?
I-I need something myself.
Yeah, right.
One more meal before bedtime.
I'm buyin'.
Hey, that's a break.
Bedtime.
[ Chattering ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
The first thing
that I'm gonna do
when I get back...
is to get some decent food.
I can dig it, man.
Let me tell you, I've eaten
worse food than this,
but then I've tasted better,
you know what I'm sayin'?
The other one over there.
Well, you
pound down the stuff
like there's no tomorrow.
I'd rather be eatin'
something else, but, uh,
right now I'm thinkin' food.
[ Kane ]
Well, you should know.
You know what it's made of.
No, man, I don't wanna talk
about what it's made of.
I'm eatin' this just to-
[ Gagging ]
What's the matter?
The food ain't
that bad, baby.
What's wrong, Kane?
[ Gagging, Retching ]
Are you choking?
What's wrong?
[ Coughing, Gasping ]
What? What?
- This is serious.
- Kane, what's the matter?
[ Gagging, Gasping ]
It's okay!
Hold him down!
Hold him-
[ Ash ]
Get the spoon in!
[ Groaning ]
Damn it!
Get it into his mouth!
I'm trying!
[ Screaming ]
[ Screams ]
[ Agonized Grunts ]
- [ Screeching ]
- [ Screaming ]
[ Lambert ]
Oh, my God! Oh, God!
No!
Don't touch it!
[ Screeching ]
[ Brett ]
Dallas?
Yeah.
Anything?
No. You?
Nothing.
You see anything?
No.
[ Loud Clank ]
[ Dallas ]
Inner hatch sealed.
Anybody wanna say anything?
This is just an ordinary prod,
like a cattle prod.
It's got a portable battery.
It's insulated
all the way here,
all the way up to here.
Just make damn sure
nobody puts their hand
on the end of it.
It shouldn't damage
the little bastard,
unless its skin's
thinner than ours.
But it will give him
a little incentive.
Now we just have
to find it.
I've taken care of that.
I've designed
this tracking device.
You just set it
to search for
a moving object, like so.
Hasn't got much of a range,
but when you get
within a certain distance,
it'll start
to give off a signal.
What's it key on?
Micro changes
in air density.
Give me a demo.
[ Whirring ]
See?
Again.
Got ya.
Two teams.
Ash, Lambert and l.
Ripley, you take
Parker and Brett.
Now, anyone see this thing,
you catch it in the net...
that Parker's holding
on his lap.
Parker, I don't want
any heroics out of you,
all right?
Catch it,
put it in the air lock,
get rid of it.
Now, channels are open
on all decks.
I want you to communicate,
keep in touch
at all times, all right?
Let's go.
I thought
you fixed 12 module.
[ Brett ]
We did.
I don't
understand it.
[ Parker ]
The circuits
must have burned out.
What do we got here?
Damn it! Hold your light
over here, would you?
Yeah, that's it.
I don't know if this
is gonna work.
If I could just put this-
put this in there.
Right.
Oh, damn it.
Check
the insulation.
Oh, shit!
[ Tracking Device Whirring ]
Steady.
According to this,
it's within five meters.
[ Indistinct Whispering ]
[ Ripley ]
Micro changes
in air density, my ass.
[ Tracking Device Beeping ]
It's within five meters.
[ Parker ]
Be careful.
[ Beeping Continues ]
[ Ripley ] Christ.
[ Parker ] Don't do that.
Don't creep up on me with that thing.
[ Ripley ]
You guys, stick together.
[ Tracker Twittering ]
Don't fail me now.
[ Parker ]
What?
What is it?
Parker, Brett,
it's in this locker!
Where?
[ Brett ]
Here, take this.
Get over there
and get the net.
Get it?
I got it. I got it.
I got it.
Wait a minute.
All right, Parker.
When I say.
All right. Now.
Easy.
[ Hissing ]
- [ All Chattering ]
- Wait! Don't let him go!
What the hell
are you doing, man?
It's the cat.
[ Laughing ]
Hey, look, now.
We had to bag it, man.
Now we might
pick it up
on the tracker again.
I'll- I'll- I'll-
Go and get it, man.
All right.
You get him.
We'll go on.
[ Sighs ]
[ Scoffs ]
Here, kitty!
Here, kitty, kitty!
Enough of that
kitty crap.
Jones.
Jonesy?
Here, Jonesy.
[ Meowing ]
[ Cat Mewing ]
Jonesy?
Here, kitty, kitty, kitty.
[ Meowing ]
Here, Jonesy.
Jonesy?
[ Faint Meowing ]
Here, kitty, kitty.
[ Meowing ]
[ Footsteps Echoing ]
[ Liquid Splashing ]
[ Chains Clinking ]
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
Here, Jonesy.
Jonesy.
Kitty, kitty.
Kitty, kitty, kitty.
Jonesy?
Hey. Hey.
Come on, Jonesy.
Come on, baby.
That's a kitty.
- That's a kitty.
- [ Hisses ]
Hey, hey.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Come on.
[ Snarling ]
[ Screaming ]
Brett!
[ Parker ]
Whatever it was, it was-
it was big and-
You're sure it took him
into the air shaft?
Disappeared into
one of the cooling ducts.
No question, it's-
it's using the air ducts
to move around.
Could he want
Brett alive?
What?
Could Brett be alive?
No. I mean,
I don't think so.
Well, this air shaft may
work to our advantage.
Here it leads up to
and comes out in
the main air lock.
All right. There's only
one big opening
along the way.
We can cover that up,
and then we...
drive it into the air lock
and zap it
into outer space.
This son of a bitch
is huge!
- I mean, it's like
a man. It's big!
- Kane's son.
Come on, Ash.
Science department
should be able to help us.
What can we do
to drive it?
Yes, well, it's adapted
remarkably well
to our atmosphere,
considering its
nutritional requirements.
- The only thing we don't
know about is temperature.
- Okay. What about temperature?
- What happens
if we change it?
- Let's try it.
I mean, most animals
retreat from fire. Yes?
Fire, yeah.
Parker, can you rig...
three or four
incinerator units?
Give me about 20 minutes.
I'll do it.
- Who gets to go
into the vent?
- I do.
No.
You and Ash...
take the main
air lock.
Parker, Lambert,
you cover up that
maintenance opening, please.
[ Lambert ]
Right.
[ Beeping ]
- [ Dallas ]
I'm at the first junction.
- Dallas, I'm right here.
- Parker?
- Yeah?
- Lambert?
We're in position.
I'm just trying to get
a reading here.
- The air lock is open.
- Okay, Ripley.
Ready.
All right. I've got
a reading on you now.
[ Tracker Beeping ]
Uh, open the hatch
to the third junction.
[ Beeping ]
[ Beeping Continues ]
[ Dallas ]
Okay, I'm through.
Ripley?
Yes.
Close all the hatches
behind me.
I'm moving on.
[ Lambert ]
Dallas, hold it a minute.
I think I got it.
Yes, I've got it.
[ Dallas ]
Where?
[ Lambert ] It's somewhere around
the third junction.
Okay, moving on.
It is right around there.
Now, Dallas, you're gonna
have to be careful.
All right.
I've reached...
the third junction,
and I'm going down.
[ Sensors Beeping ]
[ Beeping ]
The hell's the matter
with that box?
Dallas, you're gonna
have to hold your position
for a minute. I-
I've lost the signal.
What? You sure?
Look around. Are you sure
it's not there? It's got to
be around there somewhere.
[ Dallas ] Checked it out,
Lambert. You may be
getting interserence.
[ Lambert ] Dallas, are you
sure there's no sign of it?
I mean, it is there.
It's gotta be around there.
- Dallas?
- God, what is happening?
All right.
Uh, am I- am I clear, Lambert?
I want to get the hell
out of here.
[ Beeping ]
[ Lambert ]
Oh, God. It's moving
right towards you.
Um-
Move! Get out of there!
Behind you! Move!
Dallas! Move, Dallas!
Move, Dallas!
Get out!
[ Sobbing ]
Move!
The other way!
[ Screeching ]
[ Shrill Feedback ]
Dallas?
Oh, no.
Take it easy.
[ Parker ]
Dallas?
We found this laying there.
No blood.
No Dallas.
Nothing.
How come I don't hear
nobody saying nothing?
I'm thinking.
Unless somebody has got
a better idea,
we'll proceed
with Dallas's plan.
What? And end up
like the others?
Ohh. No, you're
out of your mind.
- Got a better idea?
- Yes. I say that we
abandon this ship.
We get the shuttle
and just get the hell
out of here.
We take our chances
and just hope that...
somebody picks us up.
Lambert.
The shuttle won't take four.
Then why don't we draw
straws and-
I'm not drawin' any straws.
I'm for killing
that goddamn thing right now.
[ Ripley ]
Okay.
Well, let's talk about
killing it.
[ Parker Grumbling ]
We know it's using
the air shafts- Will you
listen to me, Parker?
Shut up!
Let's hear it.
It's using the air shafts.
We don't know that.
That's the only way.
We'll move in pairs.
We'll go step by step...
and cut off
every bulkhead
and every vent...
until we have it cornered,
and then we'll blow it
the fuck out into space.
Is that acceptable
to you?
If it means killing it,
it's acceptable to me.
Obviously it means killing it.
But we have to
stick together.
How are our weapons?
The weapons are fine.
This one needs
refueling.
Will you get it, please?
Ash, go with him.
No, no. I can
manage, Ash.
Don't follow me.
Ash?
Any suggestions
from you or Mother?
No, we're still
collating.
[ Laughs ]
You're what?
You're still collating?
I find that
hard to believe.
What would you like me to do?
Just what you've
been doing, Ash.
Nothing.
I've got access
to Mother now,
and I'll get
my own answers, thank you.
All right.
[ Clicking, Beeping ]
[ Whirring ]
[ Keyboard Beeping ]
There is an explanation
for this, you know.
Is there really?
I don't wanna hear
your goddamn explanation!
[ Sobbing ]
I want- I want-
I want- I w-
Parker. Lambert?
Ash, open the door.
Ash-
Will you open the door?
Let me by, Ash.
[ Giggling ]
[ Screams ]
[ Jingling ]
Yaah!
[ Groans ]
[ Muffled Shouts ]
The hell are you doing?
[ Muffled Shouting Continues ]
Aah!
Get her up. Get her up.
[ Chittering ]
Android!
He's an android!
[ Screeching ]
Jesus!
[ Parker ]
It's a robot.
Ash is a goddamn robot!
God!
[ Parker ]
Oh! Get off me- Oh!
Holy shit!
Help! Help me get
this fucking thing off!
[ Screaming ]
Aah!
God! Jesus!
Oh, God! Oh, God!
[ Parker ]
How come the company
sent us a goddamn robot?
[ Ripley ] All I can think of is
they must've wanted the alien
for their weapons division.
He's been protecting it
right along.
Parker, will you
plug it in?
[ Parker ] I don't know why-
Because he may know
how to kill it.
[ Ripley ]
Ash, can you hear me?
Ash?
[ Distorted Voice ]
Yes, I can hear you.
- What was your special order?
- You read it.
I thought it was clear.
- What was it?
- Bring back life-form.
Priority one. All other
priorities rescinded.
The damn company!
What about our lives,
you son of a bitch?
I repeat: All other priorities
are rescinded.
[ Ripley ]
How do we kill it, Ash?
There's got to be
a way of killing it.
How- How do we do it?
You can't.
-That's bullshit!
-You still don't understand what
you're dealing with, do you?
A persect organism.
Its structural persection
is matched only
by its hostility.
You admire it.
I admire its purity.
A survivor...
unclouded by conscience,
remorse or delusions
of morality.
[ Parker ]
Look, I- I've heard
enough of this,
and I'm asking you
to pull the plug.
[ Ash ]
Last word.
What?
I can't lie to you
about your chances, but...
you have my sympathies.
We're gonna
blow up the ship.
We'll take our chances
in the shuttle.
Blow up the ship.
Good.
Come on.
When we throw the switches,
how long before the ship blows?
Ten minutes.
No bullshit.
If we ain't outta here
in ten minutes,
we won't need no rocket
to fly through space.
We're gonna need coolant
for the air support system.
You two go down,
get all the coolant
you can carry.
I'll get
the shuttle ready.
I'll give you about-
about seven minutes.
Come back up here.
I'll shut the switches off,
and we'll blow this fucker
off into space.
Okay. All right.
Come on.
Ready?
Take care
of yourself.
Seven minutes.
[ Typing ]
[ Parker On Speaker ]
Take it easy.
[ Meowing On Speaker ]
Jones.
[ Cylinders Hiss ]
Jones?
Okay, check the bottles.
How you doin'?
Fine.
Kitty.
[ Tapping Fingers ]
[ Parker On Speaker ]
Okay. Go ahead.
Jones?
Psst! Psst! Psst! Psst!
Kitty, kitty, kitty,
kitty, kitty, kitty.
Come here, Jones.
Come here.
Jones?
Come here, boy.
Come here.
Nice kitty.
Jones?
[ Rattling ]
Come here.
Come here, sweetheart.
Jones.
Jones? Jones?
Jones?
- [ Snarls ]
- [ Gasps ]
Jones!
Goddamn it!
Now I got you.
Here, sweetie.
Nice kitty.
- [ Gasps ]
- Oh, my God.
[ Parker ] Get out of the way.
[ Lambert ]
I can't get out of the way!
Get out of the way, Lambert!
It's gonna kill us!
I can't!
Lambert, for Christ's sake,
get out of the way!
Parker? Lambert-
Get out of the way, Lambert!
Parker? Lambert?
Lambert? Parker?
[ Lambert Sobbing ]
Get outta the room!
[ Screaming ]
[ Lambert Screaming ]
[ Lambert ]
Oh, God!
[ Parker Whimpering ]
[ Alien Roaring ]
[ Lambert Screaming ]
Parker?
[ Shuddering ]
[ Ripley Grunting ]
[ Alarm Beeping ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Mother ] Danger.
The emergency destruct system...
[ Alarm Sounding ]
is now activated.
The ship will detonate
in T-minus...
ten minutes.
The option to override
automatic detonation...
expires in T-minus
five minutes.
[ Alarm Continues ]
[ Mother ]
The option to override
automatic detonation...
expires in T-minus-
[ Groaning ]
[ Gasps ]
Oh-
Dallas.
[ Moaning ]
Brett.
[ Gasping ]
Oh.
[ Dallas ]
Kill me.
[ Moaning ]
Kill me!
[ Alarm Continues ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Gasps, Grunts ]
[ Grunting, Breathing Heavily ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Mother ]
The option to override
automatic detonation...
expires in T-minus...
three minutes.
[ Mother ]
The option to override...
automatic detonation
expires...
in T-minus one minute.
[ Alarm Blaring ]
Twenty-nine, 28, 27,
26, 25, 24,
23, 22,
21, 20 seconds.
Nineteen, 18,
17, 16,
15, 14, 13,
12, 11, 10 seconds.
Nine, eight, seven,
[ Gasps ]
six, five, four,
Come on!
three, two, one.
The option to override
detonation procedure...
has now expired.
Mother? I've turned
the cooling unit
back on.
Mother!
[ Mother ]
The ship will
automatically destruct...
in T-minus five minutes.
You bitch!
[ Screams ]
Goddamn it!
Jonesy.
[ Gasping ]
You now have one minute
to abandon ship.
The ship will
automatically destruct...
in T-minus one minute.
T-minus 30 seconds.
Twenty-nine, 28,
27, 26,
25, 24,
[ Beeping ]
23, 22, 21,
20 seconds.
Nineteen, 18,
17, 16,
15, 14, 13,
12, 11, 10 seconds.
[ Rapid Beeping ]
Nine, eight, seven,
six, five,
- four, three, two, one.
- [ Steady Beep ]
I got you,
you son of a bitch.
[ Meows ]
Shh, shh, shh,
shh, shh.
It's all right.
Shh, shh, shh.
[ Meows ]
It's all right.
[ Meows, Growls ]
All right. It's nice
to see you too.
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
It's okay.
[ Screams ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Air Seal Hisses ]
Come on. Come on.
♪ You are ♪
♪ My lucky star ♪
♪ You... are my ♪
♪ Lucky star ♪
♪ You ♪
Lucky, lucky, lucky,
lucky, lucky.
Okay.
[ Inhales ]
Well, come on.
♪ You are ♪
♪ My lucky star ♪
♪ You ♪
- [ Screeching ]
- ♪ You are my lucky star ♪
♪ You are my lucky star ♪
♪ You are my lucky ♪
[ Mumbling ]
[ Screeching ]
Oh, my God.
My- My lucky-
[ Breathing Heavily ]
♪ You... are my ♪
[ Gasping ]
♪ You are my ♪
♪ Lucky ♪
[ Gasping ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Screeching ]
[ Ripley ]
Final report of the commercial
starship Nostromo.
Third officer reporting.
The other members
of the crew-
Kane, Lambert,
Parker, Brett,
Ash and Captain Dallas-
are dead.
Cargo and ship destroyed.
I should reach the frontier
in about six weeks.
With a little luck,
the network will pick me up.
This is Ripley,
last survivor of the Nostromo,
signing off.
Come on, cat.
English - US - PSDH
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player