Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Do you have any idea
what they were arguing about?
- Do you speak English?
- Yeah.
No. I'm sorry,
my German is not very good.
Have you ever heard
that as couples get older...
- they lose their ability to hear each other?
- No.
Well, supposedly, men lose their ability
to hear higher-pitched sounds...
and women eventually
lose hearing in the low end.
- I guess they sort of nullify each other.
- I guess.
Nature's way of allowing couples
to grow old together...
without killing each other.
What are you reading?
Yeah.
How about you?
Look, I was thinking about going
to the lounge car sometime soon.
- Would you like to come with me?
- Yeah.
Okay.
How do you speak such good English?
I went to school for a summer
in Los Angeles.
- It's fine here?
- Yeah, this is good.
And I spent some time in London.
How do you speak such good English?
Me? I'm American.
- You're American? Are you sure?
- Yeah.
No, I'm joking. I knew you were American.
And of course,
you don't speak any other language, right?
Yeah, I get it.
I'm the crude, dumb, vulgar American
who doesn't speak any other languages...
who has no culture, right?
But I tried.
I took French for four years in high school.
When I first got to Paris...
I stood in line at the metro station.
I was practicing.
Whatever.
You know, and I get up there...
and I look at this woman
and my mind goes completely blank.
And I say,
"Listen, I need a ticket to get to..."
You know... So anyway...
So where are you headed?
Well, back to Paris.
- My classes start next week.
- You're still in school? Where do you go?
- Yeah, La Sorbonne, you know?
- Sure.
You're coming from Budapest?
- Yeah, I was visiting my grandmother.
- How is she?
She's okay.
- She's all right?
- She's fine.
- How about you? Where are you going?
- I'm going to Vienna.
Vienna? What's there?
No idea. I'm flying out of there tomorrow.
You're on holiday?
I don't really know what I'm on.
I'm just traveling around...
I've been riding the trains
the past two, three weeks.
You were visiting friends
or just on your own?
- Yeah, I had a friend in Madrid, but...
- Madrid, that's nice.
Yeah, I got one of those Eurail passes,
is what I did.
That's great.
So has this trip around Europe
been good for you?
Yeah, sure. It's been... It sucked.
What?
It's had its... Well, I'll tell you...
sitting for weeks on end looking out the
window has actually been kind of great.
What do you mean?
Well, you know, for instance...
you have ideas
that you ordinarily wouldn't have.
- What kind of ideas?
- Want to hear one?
- Yeah, tell me.
- All right.
I have this idea, okay?
For a television show.
Some friends of mine
are cable-access producers.
Do you know what that is, cable access?
Anybody can produce a show real cheap,
and they have to put it on.
I have this idea for this show that'll last
24 hours a day for a year straight, right?
What you do, is you get 365 people...
from cities all over the world...
to do these 24-hour documents
of real time.
Capturing life as it's lived.
You know, it would start
with a guy waking up in the morning...
and taking the long shower...
eating a little breakfast,
making a little coffee...
reading the paper...
Wait. All those mundane, boring things...
everybody has to do every day
of their fucking life?
I was going to say,
"The poetry of day-to-day life."
But you say it the way you say it,
I'll say it the way I say it.
- Think of it like this...
- Who's gonna watch?
Think about it like this.
Why is it that a dog sleeping in the sun...
is so beautiful? It is. It's beautiful.
But a guy standing at a bank machine...
trying to take some money out,
looks like a complete moron?
So it's like a National Geographic
program, but on people.
Yeah.
What do you think?
Yeah, I can see it. Like, 24 boring hours.
Sorry. And a three-minute sex scene
where he falls asleep right after.
Yeah, and that would be a great episode.
People would talk about that episode.
I mean, you and your friends
could do one in Paris if you wanted.
I don't know. The key, the thing
that haunts me is the distribution.
Getting the tapes from town to town,
city to city, so that the play continues...
because it'll have to play all the time,
or else it just wouldn't work.
Thank you.
Thanks.
You know what? Not service oriented.
Just an observation about Europe.
You know, my parents
never really spoke of the possibility...
of my falling in love
or getting married or having children.
Even as a little girl...
they wanted me to think
as a future career, as a...
interior designer or lawyer
or something like that.
I'd say to my dad, "I want to be a writer."
And he'd say, "Journalist."
I'd say, "I wanted to have a refuge
for stray cats." He'd say, "Veterinarian."
I'd say, "I wanted to be an actress."
He'd say, "TV newscaster."
It was this constant conversion...
of my fanciful ambition into
these practical moneymaking ventures.
I always had a pretty good
bullshit detector when I was a kid.
I always knew
when they were lying to me.
By the time I was in high school,
I was dead set...
on listening to what everybody thought
I should be doing with my life...
and just kind of doing the opposite.
No one was ever mean about it. It's just...
I could never get very excited
about other people's ambitions for my life.
But you know what?
If your parents never really,
fully contradict you about anything...
and are basically nice and supportive...
it makes it even harder
to officially complain.
Even when they're wrong,
it's this passive-aggressive shit.
You know what I mean? I hate it.
I really hate it.
Well, you know...
despite all that kind of bullshit
that comes along with it...
I remember childhood as this...
magical time. I do.
I remember when my mother
first told me about death.
My great-grandmother had just died...
and my whole family
had visited them in Florida.
I was about three,
three-and-a-half years old.
Anyway, I was in the back yard, playing...
and my sister had just taught me
how to take the garden hose...
and do it in such a way that...
it sprayed into the sun
and would make a rainbow, right?
So I was doing that...
and through the mist,
I could see my grandmother.
She was just standing there,
smiling at me.
And I held it there for a long time...
and I looked at her.
Finally, I let go of the nozzle, you know?
Then I dropped the hose,
and she disappeared.
So I run back inside and tell my parents.
And they sit me down
and give me this big crap on...
how when people die, you never see them
again, and how I'd imagined it.
But I knew what I'd seen.
I was just glad that I saw that.
I mean, I've never seen
anything like that since. But, I don't know.
It just kind of let me know
how ambiguous everything was.
Even death.
You're really lucky
you can have this attitude toward death.
I think I'm afraid of death 24 hours a day.
I swear. I mean,
that's why I'm in a train right now.
I could've flown to Paris,
but I'm too scared.
- Come on.
- I can't help it.
I know the statistics say it's safer.
Whatever.
When I'm in a plane, I can see it,
I can see the explosion.
I can see me falling through the clouds.
And I'm so scared
of those few seconds of consciousness...
before you're gonna die,
when you know for sure you're gonna die.
I can't stop thinking that way.
- It's exhausting.
- Yeah, I bet.
Really exhausting.
- I think this is Vienna.
- Yeah.
- You get off here, no?
- Yeah, what a drag.
I wish I'd met you earlier.
I really like talking to you.
Yeah, me, too.
It was really nice to meet you.
I have an admittedly insane idea,
but if I don't ask you this, it's just...
- It's gonna haunt me the rest of my life.
- What?
I want to keep talking to you.
I have no idea what your situation is...
but I feel like we have
some kind of connection. Right?
Yeah, me, too.
Great. Listen, here's the deal.
This is what we should do.
Get off with me here in Vienna
and come check out the town.
- What?
- Come on. It'll be fun.
- Come on.
- What would we do?
I don't know. All I know is I have
to catch an Austrian Airlines flight...
tomorrow morning at 9:30.
I don't have the money for a hotel...
so I was just going to walk around,
and it'd be more fun if you came with me.
If I turn out to be some kind of psycho,
you just get on the next train.
All right. Think of it like this.
Jump ahead 10, 20 years, okay?
And you're married.
Only your marriage doesn't have
that same energy that it used to have.
You start to blame your husband.
You think about all those guys
you've met in your life...
and what might've happened
if you'd picked up with one of them.
Well, I'm one of those guys. That's me.
So think of this as time travel...
from then to now to find out
what you're missing out on.
See, what this really could be
is a gigantic favor...
to you and your future husband to find out
that you're not missing out anything.
I'm just as big a loser as he is,
totally unmotivated, boring.
And you made the right choice,
and you're happy.
Let me get my bag.
- We should get a locker for all this.
- Okay.
What's your name?
My name? It's Jesse.
It's James, actually,
but everybody calls me Jesse.
You mean, Jesse James, no?
- No, just Jesse.
- I'm Celine.
- This is a nice bridge.
- Yeah.
- This is kind of weird.
- This is kind of weird, isn't it?
I mean, I feel a little awkward.
But it's all right. Right?
This is great. Let's go to some places.
Look at your book.
We're in Vienna, let's go to some places.
- Let's ask these guys.
- Okay.
Excuse me?
- Sprechen Sïe English?
- Ja. Of course.
- Do you speak German for a change?
- What?
No, it was a joke.
We just got into Vienna today,
and we're looking for something fun to do.
Like museums, exhibitions, things...
But museums are not that funny anymore
these days.
They are closing right now.
- How long are you going to be here?
- Just for tonight.
Why did you come to Vienna?
What could you be expecting?
We're on honeymoon.
Yeah, she got pregnant,
we had to get married...
I don't believe you. You're a bad liar.
This is a play we're both in...
- and we would like to invite you.
- You're actors?
Not professional actors.
Part-time actors for fun.
It's a play about a cow
and Indians searching for it.
- There are also politicians, Mexicans...
- Russians, communists.
- You have a real cow on stage?
- No, it's an actor in a cow costume.
- He's the cow.
- Yes, I am the cow.
- The cow's a bit weird.
- The cow has a disease.
She's acting a bit strange. Like a dog.
If someone throws a stick,
she fetches it and brings it back.
She can smoke with hoofs and everything.
- Great.
- As you see, there is the address.
- It's in the second district.
- Near the Prater. You know the Prater?
- The big Ferris wheel? We should go.
- The wheel, everybody knows...
Perhaps you can go to the Prater
before the play.
It starts at 21:30.
- 21:30?
- It's at 9:30.
- 9:30.
- Right.
Great. What's the name of this play?
It translates as
Brïng Me the Horns of Wïlmïngton's Cow.
I'm Wilmington's cow.
- All right.
- Great.
- You'll be there?
- We'll try.
- I'm the cow.
- You're the cow.
Goodbye.
- All right, I got an idea. Are you ready?
- Yeah.
It's Q and A time. We've known each other
a little while now.
We're stuck together, so we'll ask
each other a few direct questions.
- All right?
- So, we ask each other questions.
Yeah. You have to answer 100% honestly.
- Of course.
- Okay.
All right, first question.
- You.
- Yes, I am going to ask you.
Describe for me your first sexual feelings...
towards a person.
My first sexual feelings? Oh, my God.
I know.
Jean-Marc Fleury.
Jean-Marc Fleury?
We were at this summer camp together,
and he was a swimmer.
He had bleached-out chlorine hair
and green eyes...
and to improve his times,
he'd shave the hair off his legs and arms.
- That's disgusting.
- He was like this gorgeous dolphin.
My friend Emma had a big crush on him.
So one day, I was cutting across
the field back to my room...
and he came walking up beside me.
I told him:
"You should date Emma
because she has a big crush on you."
He turned to me and said:
"Well, that's too bad,
because I have a big crush on you."
So, yeah,
it really scared the hell out of me...
because I thought he was so fine.
Then he officially asked me out on a date.
I pretended I didn't like him.
You know,
I was so afraid of what I might do.
So I went to see him swim a few times
at the swimming competition.
He was so sexy. Really.
I mean, really sexy.
We wrote these little declarations
of love at the end of the summer...
and promised
we would keep writing forever...
and meet again very soon...
- Did you?
- Of course not.
Then this is the opportune time to tell you
that I happen to be a fantastic swimmer.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- I make note of that.
- Okay.
- So it's my turn. No?
- Yes, your turn.
Have you ever been in love?
Yes. Next question.
- What was the...
- Wait a minute.
- So I can give one-word answers?
- Why not?
After I went into such private details
about my first sexual feelings.
Those are two very different questions.
I could answer the sexual feelings thing.
But, you know, love...
I mean, what if I asked you about love?
I would have lied, but at least
I would have made up a great story.
Love is a complex issue, you know?
I mean, it's like...
Yes, I've told somebody
that I love them before, and I've meant it.
But was it totally unselfish, giving love?
Was it a beautiful thing? Not really.
You know, it's like, love...
I mean, I don't know.
You know?
Yeah. I know what you mean.
But as far as sexual feelings go
it started with an obsessive relationship...
with Miss July, 1978.
- You know Playboy magazine?
- I've heard of it.
- You know Crystal?
- No.
You don't know Crystal?
Well, I knew Crystal.
Is it my turn now? Okay.
Tell me something
that really pisses you off.
- Really drives you crazy.
- Pisses me off.
- God, everything pisses me off.
- List a couple.
I know. I hate being told by strange men...
strange men in the street...
you know, to smile to make them
feel better about their boring life.
What else?
I hate...
I hate that 300 kilometers from here,
there's a war going on...
people are dying,
and nobody knows what to do about it.
Or they don't give a shit. I don't know.
I hate that the media's trying
to control our minds.
- The media?
- Yeah, the media.
It's very subtle,
but it's a new form of fascism, really.
I hate...
I hate when I'm in a foreign country,
especially in America, the worst...
each time I wear black or lose my temper
or say anything about anything...
they always go,
"Oh, it's so French. It's so cute."
I hate that. I can't stand that. Really.
Is that all?
Well, there's a lot of things, but...
- So it's my turn.
- Okay.
- You're gonna answer.
- Yes, I'll answer.
What's a problem for you?
You, probably.
What?
I had a thought the other day
that kind of...
qualifies as a problem.
What is it?
It was a thought I had on the train, so...
Okay. All right.
Do you believe in reincarnation?
Yeah, it's interesting.
A lot of people talk about past lives
and things like that, you know?
Even if they don't believe in it
in some specific way...
people have a notion
of an eternal soul, right?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
This is my thought: 50,000 years ago
there's not even a million people.
Ten thousand years ago, there's, like,
two million people on the planet.
Now there's between
five and six billion people on the planet.
If we all have our own individual,
unique soul...
where did they all come from?
Are modern souls only a fraction
of the original souls?
Because if they are, that represents
a 5,000 to one split of each soul...
in just the last 50,000 years,
which is a blip in the Earth's time.
At best, we're these tiny fractions...
of people walking...
Is that why we're so scattered?
Is that why we're so specialized?
Wait a minute, I'm not sure. I don't...
Yeah, I know.
It's a totally scattered thought.
- Which is kind of why it makes sense.
- Yeah, I agree with you.
Let's get off this damn train.
- This place is pretty neat.
- Yeah.
There's even a listening booth over there.
Have you heard of this singer?
I think she's American.
A friend told me about her.
Do you want to go see
if that listening booth still works?
Yeah, okay.
Look at this. This is beautiful.
Quick. It's leaving.
Look, there's a rabbit.
Yeah.
Hey there, rabbit.
It's so cute.
I visited this as a young teenager.
It left a bigger impression on me
at that time...
- than any of the museums we went to.
- Yeah?
- It's tiny.
- I know.
There was this little old man
that talked to us.
He was the groundskeeper.
He explained that
most of the people are buried here...
that washed up on the bank of the Danube.
How old are these?
Around the beginning of the century or so.
It's called the cemetery of the no-name...
because they often didn't know
who these people were.
Maybe a first name, that's all.
Why were all the bodies washing up?
I think some were from accidents
on boats and things like that.
But most of them were suicides
that jumped in the river.
I always liked the idea of all those
unknown people lost in the world.
When I was a little girl, I thought...
if none of your family or friends
knew you were dead...
then it's like not really being dead.
People can invent
the best and the worst for you.
Here she is, I think.
Yeah, this is the one I remember the most.
She was only 13 when she died.
That meant something to me, you know,
I was that age when I first saw this.
Now I'm 10 years older,
and she's still 13, I guess.
That's funny.
That's the Danube over there.
- That's a river, right?
- Yeah.
This is...
gorgeous.
Yeah, this is beautiful.
I mean, we got...
We got a sunset here.
- Yeah.
- We got the Ferris wheel.
It seems like...
this would be a...
What?
You know...
Are you trying to say you want to kiss me?
Yeah?
- But you know what?
- What?
It doesn't matter what generation
you're born into.
Look at my parents.
They were angry, young May '68 people
revolting against everything.
The government,
their conservative Catholic backgrounds.
I was born, and my father
went on to become a successful architect.
We traveled around the world
while he built bridges, towers and stuff.
I mean, I really can't complain
about anything.
They love me more
than anything in the world...
and I've been raised
with all the freedom they fought for.
And yet, for me now,
it's another type of fight.
We have to deal with the same old shit,
but we can't really know...
who or, you know, what the enemy is.
I don't know if there really is an enemy.
Everybody's parents fucked them up.
Rich kids' parents gave them too much.
Poor kids', not enough.
Too much attention, not enough attention.
They either left them
or they taught them the wrong things.
My parents are just two people
who didn't like each other very much...
who decided to get married
and have a kid.
They tried their best to be nice to me.
Did your parents divorce?
Yeah, finally.
They should have done it a lot sooner.
They stuck together
for the well-being of my sister and I.
Thank you very much.
I remember my mother once told me,
right in front of my father...
they were having a fight,
that he didn't want to have me.
That he was pissed off
when he found out she was pregnant.
That I was a big mistake.
That really shaped the way I think.
I always saw the world as this place
where I really wasn't meant to be.
That's so sad.
Well, I mean,
I eventually kind of took pride in it.
You know, like my life was my own doing,
or something.
You know,
like I was crashing the big party.
That's the way to see it.
My parents are still married
and I guess they're happy.
But I think it's a healthy process to rebel
against everything that came before.
Yeah.
You know, I've been wondering lately...
do you know anyone
who's in a happy relationship?
Yeah, sure.
You know, I know happy couples.
But I think they lie to each other.
Yeah.
People can live their whole life as a lie.
My grandmother,
she was married to this man...
and I always thought
she had a simply, uncomplicated love life.
But she just confessed to me
that she spent her whole life...
dreaming about another man
she was always in love with.
She just accepted her fate. It's so sad.
In the same time, I love the idea
that she had all those emotions...
and feelings I never thought
she would have had.
I guarantee you it was better that way.
If she'd known him,
he'd have disappointed her eventually.
- How do you know? You don't know them.
- I know.
People put romantic projections
on everything.
It's not based on any kind of reality.
- Romantic projections?
- Yeah.
Mr. Romantic up in the Ferris wheel?
"Oh, kiss me. The sunset.
Oh, it's so beautiful."
All right. Tell me about your grandmother.
What were you saying about her?
Check these guys out.
"Hans, I have a confession to make.
"I'm not wearing underwear
underneath this."
"Oh, really? Does that frighten you?"
- Can I tell you a secret?
- Yeah.
Come here.
- What?
- Come here.
Look at this palm reader.
She's interesting looking.
Yeah.
- What?
- I just made eye contact.
- She's not coming over here.
- She is.
Shit.
Oh, no.
- You want your palm read?
- No.
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure.
- Okay.
- Hello.
Here she is.
I want your palm read.
Yeah. How much is it?
- For you, 50 schillings. Okay?
- Okay.
So you have been on a journey...
and you're a stranger to this place.
You are an adventurer.
A seeker.
An adventurer in your mind.
You are interested
in the power of the woman.
In the woman's deep strength
and creativity.
You're becoming this woman.
You need to resign yourself
to the awkwardness of life.
Only if you find peace within yourself...
will you find true connection with others.
That is a stranger to you?
I guess so.
You will be all right. He's learning.
Okay. Money.
You're both stars. Don't forget.
When the stars exploded
billions of years ago...
they formed everything that is this world.
Everything we know is stardust.
So don't forget, you are stardust.
That's very nice and all.
I mean, that we're all stardust,
and you're becoming this great woman.
I hope you don't take that
any more seriously...
than some horoscope
in a daily syndicated newspaper.
What are you talking about?
She knew I was on vacation
and we didn't know each other...
and that I was going
to become this great woman.
But what was that
"I am learning" bullshit?
That's way condescending, you know?
I mean, she wasn't even doing me.
I mean, if opportunists
like that ever had to tell the real truth...
it would put their asses out of business.
I mean, just once
I'd love to see some little old lady...
save up all her money
to go to the fortuneteller.
She'd get there all excited about hearing
her future, and the woman would say:
"Tomorrow and all your remaining days
will be exactly like today...
"a tedious collection of hours.
"And you will have no new passions
and no new thoughts...
"and no new travels.
"And when you die,
you'll be completely forgotten.
"Fifty schillings, please."
That I'd like to see.
It's so funny how...
she almost didn't notice you.
It's weird. I wonder why.
- She was really wise and intense.
- Yeah.
- I really loved what she said.
- Of course you do.
You pay to hear what makes
you feel good about yourself.
Maybe there's a seedy section of Vienna.
We can buy a hit of crack.
- Would you like that? Yeah?
- You're so...
Stardust.
There's an exhibition.
Yeah. I guess we'll miss it.
It doesn't start until next week.
Yeah, I think so.
I actually saw this one
a few years ago in a museum.
I stared and stared at it.
Must have been 45 minutes.
I love it.
La voïe ferrée. It's great.
I love the way the people seem
to be dissolving into the background.
Look at this one.
It's like the environments
are stronger than the people.
His human figures
are always so transitory.
It's funny. Transitory?
Transitory.
- You think this is open?
- I don't know. Let's try it.
I was in an old church like this...
with my grandmother
a few days ago in Budapest.
Even though I reject
most of the religious thing...
I can't help but feeling
for those people that come here...
lost or in pain, guilt...
Looking for some kind of answers.
It fascinates me how a single place
can join so much pain and happiness...
of so many generations.
You're close with your grandmother?
Yeah.
I think it's because I always have
this strange feeling...
that I'm this very old woman
laying down, about to die.
You know, that my life
is just her memories or something.
That's so wild.
I always think
that I'm still this 13-year-old boy...
who doesn't really know
how to be an adult...
pretending to live my life...
taking notes for when
I'll really have to do it.
Like I'm in a dress rehearsal
for a junior high play.
That's funny.
Then up there in the Ferris wheel,
it was like this...
very old woman
kissing this very young boy. Right?
Do you know anything about the Quakers,
the Quaker religion?
No, not much.
I went to this Quaker wedding once
and it was fantastic.
What they do is...
the couple comes in and they kneel down
in front of the whole congregation...
and they just stare at each other.
Nobody says a word unless they feel
that God moves them to speak...
or say something.
And then, after an hour or so of just...
staring at each other they're married.
That's beautiful. I like that.
This is a horrible story.
What?
- It's not the appropriate place to tell it.
- What?
Well, I was driving around
with this buddy of mine.
He's a big atheist, you know.
And he came to a stop
next to this homeless guy.
My buddy takes out a $100 bill...
and leans out the window...
and he says, "Do you believe in God?"
And the guy looks at my friend,
he looks at the money.
He says:
"Yes, I do."
My friend says, "Wrong answer."
We drove away.
- That's mean.
- Yeah.
Would you be in Paris by now
if you hadn't gotten off the train with me?
No, not yet.
What would you be doing?
I'd be hanging around the airport,
reading magazines...
crying in my coffee
because you didn't come with me.
I'd probably gotten off the train
in Salzburg with someone else.
Oh, yeah? Oh, I see.
So I'm just a dumb American momentarily
decorating your blank canvas?
I'm having a great time.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Me, too.
I'm glad because no one knows I'm here...
and I don't know anyone that would
tell me all those bad things you've done.
- I'll tell you some.
- Yeah, I'm sure.
You know, you hear
so much shit about people.
I always feel like the general of an army
when I start dating a guy.
Plotting my strategy and maneuverings...
knowing his weak points,
what would hurt him, seduce him.
It's horrible.
If we were with each other always...
what would be the first thing
about me that would drive you mad?
No. I'm not going to answer this question.
I dated this girl once
who used to always ask me that.
"What about me bugs you?"
Finally, I said, "I don't think
you handle criticism too well."
She flew into a rage
and broke up with me. That's a true story.
All she ever wanted to do...
was to have an excuse to tell me
what she thought was wrong with me.
- Is that what you want?
- What?
- Something about me bugs you?
- No.
- What is it about me bugs you?
- Nothing at all.
If it had to be something,
what would it be?
if I had to think about it...
I kind of didn't really like this reaction
at the palm reader.
You were like this rooster prick.
What the hell is a rooster prick?
You were like a boy whining because
all the attention wasn't focused on him.
All right, listen.
This woman robs you blind, okay?
You were like a boy
walking by an ice-cream store...
crying because his mother
won't buy him a milkshake.
I don't care what this charlatan
has to say about...
Hello?
What?
I understand a little bit,
but he doesn't at all. I'm sorry.
Okay.
- May I ask you a question?
- Yeah.
I would like to make a deal with you.
I mean, instead of just asking you
for money, I will ask you for a word.
You give me a word, I take the word...
and then I will write a poem
with the word inside.
And if you like it, if you like my poem...
if you feel it adds something to your life
in any way...
then you can pay me
whatever you feel like.
I'll write in English, of course.
- Okay. Great.
- All right. Great.
So?
Pick a word.
A word.
- Milkshake.
- Milkshake? Good.
I was gonna say "rooster prick."
But great. Milkshake.
Milkshake?
Okay, milkshake.
- All right, so...
- Good.
I gotta say,
I like this Viennese variation of bum.
I like what he said
about adding something to your life.
So, were we having our first fight
back there?
- No.
- I think so. I think we were.
Even if we were, why does everyone think
conflict is so bad?
There's a lot of good things
coming out of conflict.
Yeah, I guess so.
I always think
if I could just accept the fact...
that my life was supposed to be difficult,
that's what's to be expected...
then I might not get so pissed off about it.
And I'd just be glad
when something nice happens.
Maybe that's why I'm still in school.
It's easier to have something
to fight against.
We've all had such competitiveness
ingrained in us.
I can be doing the most nothing thing.
I can be throwing some darts
or shooting some pool.
Then all of a sudden,
I feel it come over me.
I have got to win.
Is that why you tried to get me
off the train? Competitiveness?
- What do you mean?
- Okay.
- I got you a poem.
- All right.
Will you read it to us?
Sure. Okay.
"Daydream delusion
"Limousine eyelash
"Oh, baby, with your pretty face
"Drop a tear in my wineglass
"Look at those big eyes
"See what you mean to me
"Sweet cakes and milkshakes
"I am a delusion angel
"I'm a fantasy parade
"I want you to know what I think
Don't want you to guess anymore
"You have no idea where I came from
"We have no idea where we're going
"Lodged in life, like branches in the river
"Flowing downstream
caught in the current
"I carry you, you'll carry me
"That's how it could be
"Don't you know me?
"Don't you know me by now?"
Great.
- Thanks.
- Thanks, man.
Here you go.
- Thanks.
- All right.
- Here. Thank you.
- Thank you.
Good luck.
- Bye.
- It was wonderful, no?
- Yeah.
- What?
- He probably didn't just write that.
He wrote it,
but he probably plugs that word in.
You know, whatever, "milkshake."
- What do you mean?
- Nothing. I loved it. It was great.
- You know what drives me crazy?
- What?
People always talk about how great
technology is, how it saves all this time.
But what good is saved time
if nobody uses it?
- It just turns into more busy work.
- Yeah.
You never hear anyone say, "With the time
I've saved by using my word processor...
"I'm gonna go to a Zen monastery
and hang out."
- You don't hear that.
- Time is abstract anyway.
- Were you looking at this girl?
- What?
Nothing.
- You wanna go in here?
- What?
- Yeah. It's a club, no?
Wanna go? Hello.
Fifty schillings.
- Each.
- I got a 100. Here, I got it.
I'll buy you a beer. Thank you.
- You gonna buy me a beer?
- Yeah.
You think Old Milwaukee
is expensive here?
We haven't talked about this yet,
but are you dating anyone?
You got a boyfriend waiting on you
back in Paris or anything like that?
- No, not right now.
- But you did.
- We broke up six months ago.
- Six months ago?
- Yeah.
- I'm sorry.
I mean, I'm not that sorry.
But tell me about it.
No, no way. I can't. It's really boring.
Come on. Tell me about it.
Okay. I was really disappointed.
I thought this one would last a while.
I mean, he was very stupid,
ugly, bad in bed, alcoholic...
- You know.
- A real prize winner.
I was kind of giving him a favor.
But he left me,
saying I loved him too much.
I was blocking his artistic expression
or some shit like that.
But anyway, I was traumatized...
and became totally obsessed with him.
So I went to a shrink...
and it came up that I had written
this little stupid story...
about this woman
trying to kill her boyfriend...
and how she was gonna do it
with all the intricate details...
- of how to do it and not get caught...
- She was gonna kill her boyfriend?
Yeah, she was.
It's nothing I would do,
but it was just some writing.
No, I understand.
But anyway this stupid shrink believed
everything I told her.
It was my first time seeing her.
She said she had to call the police.
- She had to call the police?
- Yes.
She was... Merde!
She was totally convinced
I was really gonna do it.
Even though I had explained
it was just some writing.
She said, looking deep into my eyes:
"The way you said it
I know you are going to do it.
"The way you said it."
She was totally out of her mind.
- It was my first and last session.
- So what happened then?
I totally got over him.
But now I'm obsessed...
that he's gonna die from an accident
or 1000 kilometers away.
And I'm gonna be the one accused.
Why is it you become obsessed
with people you don't like that much?
- You know what I mean?
- I don't know.
So how about you?
- What?
- Are you with anyone?
It's funny how we managed to avoid
this subject for so long, isn't it?
But now you have to tell me.
Well, I kind of see love...
as this escape for two people
who don't know how to be alone.
I mean, it's funny.
People always talk about how...
Love is this totally unselfish, giving thing.
But if you think about it,
there's nothing more selfish.
I know.
So, who just broke up with you?
What?
You sound like you've just been hurt.
- Do I?
- Yeah.
All right.
Big confession.
I should've told you this earlier
or something.
I didn't come to Europe just to hang out...
and read Hemingway in Paris
and shit like that.
I saved up my money all spring
to fly to Madrid...
and spend the summer with my girlfriend
who's been on...
- Your girlfriend?
- My ex-girlfriend...
who has been on this asinine
art history program for the last year.
Anyway, I got here.
We were reunited at long last...
and we went out to dinner, our first night,
with six of her friends.
Pedro, Antonio, Gonzalo,
Maria, Suzy from home.
She avoided being alone with me for
the first couple of days we were there...
and I stuck around for a while just to let it
sink in that she wished I hadn't come.
So I bought the cheapest flight out,
this one leaving out of Vienna tomorrow...
but it didn't leave for a couple weeks,
so I bought this Eurail pass.
You know what's the worst thing
about somebody breaking up with you?
It's when you remember
how little you thought...
about the people you broke up with...
and you realize that that is how little
they're thinking about you.
You'd like to think
you're both in all this pain...
but really, they're just,
"Hey, I'm glad you're gone."
Believe me, I know.
- You should look at bright colors.
- What?
That's what the shrink told me.
I was paying her 900 francs an hour
to hear that I was a homicidal maniac...
but I could shift my obsession
if I would concentrate on bright colors.
Did it work?
- Didn't help your pinball.
- Well, no.
Yeah, well, you know,
I haven't killed anyone lately.
Not lately? That's good. You're cured then.
There's these breeds of monkeys,
and all they do is have sex...
all the time, you know?
They turn out to be the least violent,
the most peaceful, the most happy.
So maybe fooling around is not so bad.
- Are you talking about monkeys?
- Yes, I'm talking about monkeys.
- I thought so.
- Why?
I never heard this one.
But it reminds me
of this perfect male argument...
to justify them fooling around.
Women monkeys are fooling around, too.
Everybody's fooling around.
Yeah, that's cute.
I have this awful, paranoid thought...
that feminism
was mostly invented by men...
so they could fool around a little more.
"Woman, free your mind,
free your body. Sleep with me.
"We're all happy and free,
as long as I can fuck as much as I can."
All right. But maybe there's
some biological things at work here.
If you had an island...
and there were 99 women on the island
and only one man...
in a year,
you'd have the possibility of 99 babies.
But if you have an island
with 99 men and only one woman...
in a year,
you have the possibility of only one baby.
So...
You know what?
On this island, I think there will be
only maybe 43 men left.
They would've killed each other
trying to fuck this poor woman.
On the other island...
there would be 99 women, 99 babies,
and no more man.
Because they would've gotten together
and eaten him alive.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
There's something to that.
On some level, women don't mind the idea
of destroying a man.
I was once walking down the street
with my ex-girlfriend...
and we'd just walked by these four
thuggy-looking guys next to a Camaro.
And one of them says,
"Hey, baby, nice ass!"
So I'm like, "No big deal.
I won't get uptight about this."
- Plus, there were four of them.
- Exactly.
She turns and says,
"Fuck you, dickheads!"
And I'm like, "Okay. Wait a minute here."
They're not gonna come over
and kick her ass.
So who just got pushed to the frontline
on that one?
Women say they hate it
if you're all territorial and protective...
but if it suits them, then they'll tell you
you're being all unmanly, or wimpy, or...
You know what? I don't think
women really want to destroy men.
Even if they want to, they don't succeed.
I'm sure even men
are destroying women...
or are able or capable of destroying
women, much more than women.
Anyway, it's depressing.
I mean, you know what?
- You wanna stop talking about this?
- I hate it.
Men, women, it's... There's no end to this.
- It's like a skipping record.
- Yeah.
Every couple's been
having this conversation forever.
And nobody came up with anything.
I saw a documentary on that.
It's a birth dance.
- A birth dance?
- Yeah.
Should I give her some money?
Everything that's interesting
costs a little bit of money.
So, a birth dance?
Looked a little bit
like a mating dance to me.
No, but really.
Women used it when giving birth.
In some part of the world, they still do it.
The woman in labor enters a tent...
and the women of her tribe
surround her and dance.
They encourage the birthing woman
to dance with them...
so as to make the birth less painful.
And when the baby is born,
they all dance in celebration.
I don't think my mom
would've gone for that.
I like the idea of dancing
as a common function.
- Something everybody participates in.
- I know.
I heard about this old guy who was
watching some young people dance.
He said, "How beautiful.
"They're trying to shake off their genitals,
and become angels."
- I like that.
- One question, though, back there.
When the women are dancing
and being all spiritual and stuff...
where are the men?
Are we out food gathering?
Are we not invited? You all don't need us?
Men are lucky
we don't bite off their heads after mating.
Certain insects do that,
like spiders and stuff?
We let you live.
What are you complaining about?
See, you're officially kidding.
But there's something to that.
- You keep bringing stuff like that up.
- What?
- Yeah.
- No, wait a minute.
Talking seriously here...
I feel this pressure of being a strong
and independent icon of womanhood...
and not making it look like my whole life
is revolving around some guy.
But loving someone...
and being loved means so much to me.
I always make fun of it and stuff...
but isn't everything we do in life
a way to be loved a little more?
I don't know.
Sometimes I dream...
about being a good father
and a good husband.
And sometimes it feels really close.
But then other times...
it seems silly...
like it would ruin my whole life.
And it's not just a fear of commitment...
or that I'm incapable of caring or loving
because I can.
It's just that,
if I'm totally honest with myself...
I think I'd rather die knowing
that I was really good at something.
That I had excelled in some way...
than that I had just been
in a nice, caring relationship.
I had worked for this older man,
and once he told me...
that he had spent all of his life
thinking about his career and his work.
He was 52, and it suddenly struck him...
that he had never really
given anything of himself.
His life was for no one and nothing.
He was almost crying saying that.
You know, I believe
if there's any kind of God...
it wouldn't be in any of us,
not you or me...
but just this little space in between.
If there's any kind of magic in this world...
it must be in the attempt of understanding
someone, sharing something.
I know it's almost impossible to succeed...
but who cares, really?
The answer must be in the attempt.
I really think this is a civilization
in decline. Look at the service.
- The service?
- Where is the waitress?
In New York, she'd be out of a job.
I'm gonna call my best friend in Paris...
who I'm supposed to have lunch with
in eight hours, okay?
- Pick up.
- What?
- Pick up the phone.
- Hello?
I've been working on my English recently.
You wanna talk in English, for laughs?
Yeah, okay. That's a good idea.
I don't think I'll be able to make it
for lunch today. I'm sorry.
I met a guy on the train, and I got off
with him in Vienna. We're still there.
Are you crazy?
Probably.
- He's Austrian? He's from there?
- No.
He's passing through. He's American.
He's going back home tomorrow morning.
Why did you get off the train with him?
Well, he convinced me.
I mean, actually, I was ready
to get off the train with him...
after talking to him a short while.
He was so sweet, I couldn't help it.
We were in the lounge car
and he began to talk about him...
as a little boy
seeing his great-grandmother's ghost.
I think that's when I fell for him.
Just the idea of this little boy
with all those beautiful dreams.
He trapped me.
And he's so cute.
He has beautiful blue eyes...
nice pink lips...
greasy hair.
I love it.
He's kind of tall, and he's a little clumsy.
I like to feel his eyes on me
when I look away.
He kind of kisses like an adolescent.
It's so cute.
- What?
- Yeah, we kissed.
It was so adorable.
As the night went on,
I began to like him more and more.
But I'm afraid he's scared of me.
I told him the story about the woman
that kills her ex-boyfriend and stuff.
He must be scared to death.
He must be thinking
I'm this manipulative, mean woman.
I just hope
he doesn't feel that way about me.
Because, you know me,
I'm the most harmless person.
The only person
I could really hurt is myself.
I don't think he's scared of you.
I think he's crazy about you.
- Really?
- I've known you a long time.
I got a good feeling.
You gonna see him again?
We haven't talked about that yet.
Okay, it's your turn. You call your friend.
- Okay?
- All right.
I usually get
this guy's answering machine.
Hi, dude. What's up?
Hey, Frank. How you been?
I'm glad you're home.
Cool. Yeah. So, how was Madrid?
Madrid sucked.
Lisa and I had our long overdue meltdown.
Too bad. I told you, no?
Yeah. The long-distance thing
just never works.
I was only in Madrid for a couple days.
I got a cheaper flight out of Vienna.
You know,
it really wasn't that much cheaper. I just...
I couldn't go home right away.
I didn't want to see anybody I knew.
I just wanted to be a ghost,
completely anonymous.
- So are you okay now?
- Yeah.
I'm great. That's the thing.
I'm rapturous. And I'll tell you why.
I met somebody on my last night
in Europe. Can you believe it?
- That's incredible.
- I know.
You know how they say
we're all each other's demons and angels?
Well, she was literally a Botticelli angel...
just telling me
that everything was gonna be okay.
How did you meet?
On the train.
She was sitting next to this weird couple
that started fighting, so she had to move.
She sat right across the aisle from me.
So we started to talk.
She didn't like me much at first.
She's super smart...
very passionate...
and beautiful.
And I was so unsure of myself.
I thought everything I said
sounded so stupid.
- Man, I wouldn't worry about that.
- No.
No, I'm sure she was not judging you.
No, and by the way, she sat next to you.
I'm sure she did it on purpose.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Us men are so stupid. We don't
understand anything about women.
They act strange, the little I know of them.
Don't they?
Yeah.
I feel like
this is some dream world we're in.
Yeah, it's so weird.
It's like our time together is just ours.
It's our own creation.
It must be like I'm in your dream
and you're in mine or something.
What's so cool is that this whole evening,
all our time together...
shouldn't officially be happening.
Yeah, I know. Maybe that's why
this feels so otherworldly.
But then the morning comes
and we turn into pumpkins, right?
I know.
But now, you're supposed
to produce the glass slipper...
and see if it fits.
It'll fit.
This friend of mine had a kid...
and it was a home birth,
so he was there helping out.
But he said
at that profound moment of birth...
he was watching his child experiencing life
for the first time...
trying to take its first breath.
All he could think about was
that he was looking at something...
that was gonna die someday.
He just couldn't get it out of his head.
And I think that's so true.
Everything is so finite.
But don't you think that's
what makes our time...
and specific moments so important?
Yeah, I know.
It's the same for us tonight, though.
After tomorrow, we're probably
never gonna see each other again, right?
You don't think
we'll ever see each other again?
What do you think?
Actually, I don't know.
- I hadn't planned another trip...
- Me, too.
I live in Paris, you live in the U.S.
I understand.
I'd hate to make you fly.
You hate to fly, right?
I'm not so scared of flying.
I mean, I could.
Well, if you were gonna come to the U. S...
or if, you know, if I...
Or, you know, I could come back here.
What?
No, let's just be rational adults about this.
Maybe we should try something different.
It's not so bad
if tonight is our only night, right?
People exchange numbers, addresses.
They end up writing once,
calling each other once or twice.
Right. Fizzles out.
Yeah, I don't want that. I hate that.
I hate that, too.
Why does everybody think
relationships should last forever, anyway?
Yeah, why? It's stupid.
But you think tonight's it?
I mean, that tonight's our only night?
It's the only way, no?
Well, all right.
Let's do it.
No delusions, no projections.
We'll just make tonight great.
- Okay, let's do that.
- Okay.
We should do some kind of handshake.
Give me your hand.
To our one and only night together...
and the hours that remain.
What?
It's just... It's depressing, no?
Now the only thing
we're gonna think of is...
when we'll have
to say goodbye tomorrow.
We could say goodbye now.
Then we won't have to worry about it.
- Now?
- Yeah.
Say goodbye.
- Bye.
- Goodbye.
Au revoïr.
- Later.
- Later, yeah.
Here's the plan.
You're gonna grab the glasses,
and I'm gonna get the wine.
- Red wine.
- Red wine. Right.
- You think you can do that?
- No problem.
- Wish me luck.
- Good luck.
Hello.
- Do you speak English?
- A bit.
Yeah? A bit? Well, all right.
I'm having kind of an odd situation
which is that...
You see that girl over there?
- Yeah.
- This is our only night together...
and she...
Here's the problem.
The problem is
that she wants a bottle of red wine...
and I don't have any money.
But I was thinking
that you might want to...
give me the address of this bar and
I would promise to send you the money...
and you'd be making our night complete.
- You would send me the money?
- Yes.
Your hand?
Okay.
- For the greatest night in your life.
- Thank you very much.
So often I've been with people
and shared beautiful moments...
like traveling or staying up all night
and watching the sunrise.
And I knew those were special moments.
But something was always wrong.
I wished I'd been with someone else.
I knew that what I was feeling...
exactly what was so important to me,
they didn't understand.
But I'm happy to be with you.
You couldn't possibly know
why a night like this...
is so important to my life right now,
but it is.
- This is a great morning.
- It is a great morning.
Do you think we'll have others like this?
- What?
- What about our rational, adult decision?
Oh, yeah.
I know what you mean
about wishing somebody wasn't there.
It's just, usually it's myself
that I wish I could get away from.
Seriously, think about this.
I have never been anywhere
that I haven't been.
I've never had a kiss
when I wasn't one of the kissers.
You know, I've never gone to the movies
when I wasn't there in the audience.
I've never been out bowling
if I wasn't there making some stupid joke.
I think that's why so many people
hate themselves. Seriously.
It's just that they are sick to death
of being around themselves.
Let's say that you and I were together
all the time.
You'd start to hate
a lot of my mannerisms.
The way that every time
that we would have people over...
I'd be insecure,
and I'd get a little too drunk.
Or the way I tell the same stupid,
pseudo-intellectual story...
again and again.
You see, I've heard all those stories...
so of course I'm sick of myself.
But being with you...
it's made me feel
like I was somebody else.
I mean, the only other way
to lose yourself like that is...
you know, dancing, or alcohol...
or drugs, or stuff like that.
Fucking.
Fucking, yeah. That's one way.
Do you know what I want?
What?
To be kissed.
Well, I could do that.
Wait.
I have to say something stupid.
All right.
It's very stupid.
I don't think we should sleep together.
I want to, but since we're never
going to see each other again...
it'll make me feel bad.
I'll wonder who else you're with.
I'll miss you.
I know. It's not very adult.
Maybe it's a female thing. I can't help it.
Let's see each other again.
No, I don't want you to break our vow
just so you can get laid.
I don't want to just get laid.
I want to, I mean...
I mean, I think we should.
We die in the morning, right?
- I think we should.
- Then it's like some male fantasy.
Meet a French girl on the train,
fuck her and never see her again.
And have this story to tell.
I don't want to be a great story.
I don't want this great evening
to just have been for that.
Okay, we don't have to have sex.
It's not a big deal.
You don't want to see me again?
No, of course I do.
If somebody gave me
the choice right now...
of to never see you again,
or to marry you...
I would marry you.
Maybe that's a lot of romantic bullshit...
but people have gotten married
for a lot less.
Actually...
I think I decided I wanted to sleep
with you when we got off the train.
Now that we've talked so much,
I don't know anymore.
Why do we make everything
so complicated?
I don't know.
What's the first thing you'll do
when you get back to Paris?
Call my parents. What about you?
I don't know. I'll probably go
pick up my dog. He's with a friend.
You have a dog? I love dogs.
- You do?
- Yeah.
- Oh, shit.
- What?
I don't know. We're back in real time.
I know. I hate that.
What is that?
- Sounds like a harpsichord.
- Check that out.
Somebody's playing.
That's cool.
- Can we dance to the harpsichord?
- Of course.
- Wow.
- What?
I'm gonna take your picture...
so I never forget you...
or all this.
Okay, me, too.
"The years shall run like rabbits"
What?
Nothing.
I have this recording of Dylan Thomas...
reading a W. H. Auden poem.
He's got a great voice.
It's like:
"All the clocks in the city
"began to whir and chime:
“O let not Time deceive you
“you cannot conquer Time
“In headaches and in worry
“vaguely life leaks away
“And Time will have his fancy
“Tomorrow or today”
Something like that.
That's good.
When you talked earlier
about after a few years...
how a couple would begin
to hate each other...
by anticipating their reactions,
or getting tired of their mannerisms.
I think it would be the opposite for me.
I think I can really fall in love
when I know everything about someone.
The way he's gonna part his hair,
which shirt he's gonna wear that day...
knowing the exact story he'd tell
in a given situation.
I'm sure that's when I know
I'm really in love.
- Hey, guess what.
- What?
We didn't go to those guys' play.
- Play?
- Yeah.
- The cow?
Oh, yeah, we didn't.
Oh, no. We missed it.
You know what bus
to take to the airport?
No problem.
- I should get on this one.
- Right here. You wanna get on there?
- I guess this is it, no?
- Yeah.
I really...
- You know...
- Yeah, I know. Me, too.
Have a great life.
Have fun with everything you're gonna do.
- Good luck with school and all that.
- Okay.
I hate this.
Me, too. The train is about to leave.
You know all this bullshit we're talking
about not seeing each other again?
- I don't want that.
- I don't want to, either.
- You don't?
- I waited for you to say it.
Why didn't you say something?
- I was afraid you didn't wanna see me.
- All right, what do you wanna do?
Maybe we should meet here
in five years or something.
Five years? That's a long time.
It's awful.
It's like a sociological experiment.
- How about one year?
- One year. All right.
- How about six months?
- Six months?
- It's gonna be freezing.
- Yeah.
Who cares? We come here,
we go somewhere else.
Six months from now or last night?
Last night. Six months from last night,
which was June 16.
So track nine,
six months from now at 6:00 at night.
December.
It's a train ride for you,
but I gotta fly all the way here.
But I'm gonna be here.
- Okay, me, too.
- All right.
- We won't call, write or...
- No, it's depressing.
- Yeah, okay.
- All right.
Your train's gonna leave. Say goodbye.
Bye.
Goodbye.
Au revoïr.
Later.
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/8ys
Help other users to choose the best subtitles